[Music]
Hello and welcome to the Junkyard Love.
>> Hey, everything's going to be all right.
>> It's all good. It's all good.
>> The Junkyard Love podcast.
[Music]
to the junkyard.
>> So, we were just talking about YouTube.
I I So, I think what happens with me
when I watch YouTube, I I almost get the
same thing with video games. Like, I I
don't really play many video games. My
attention is I I think they're cool, but
it's just they aren't something I spend
a ton of my time on. And I noticed if I
do end up playing video games, as much
as it's like, yeah, I'm having fun.
Maybe I'm having fun with friends.
That's important. that's valuable. But I
start to very quickly have this ticking
clock or like a air horn of, hey, you're
not doing something valuable. You're
consuming rather than creating or
outputting, you know, and you're a
creative. So, I have this alarm that
goes off. And sometimes I feel if I'm
watching too many like like TV shows or
uh movies, whatever. I love movies and
everything, but I'm more prone to listen
to the the modern podcasts, the like
what are the philosophers talking about
right now? How can I expand my mind? how
can I um you know in some ways maybe
it's not super healthy to like listen to
all these like self-development
self-help like here's what you need to
work on today but I am just way more
drawn to that like I just you know I'm
way more prone to listen to something
that I feel is giving me value in my
life and making me better versus
something that I'm consuming I don't
know
>> well it makes sense well it activates
different parts of your brain so when
you're listening to somebody's ideas
you're developing your own whether that
is you're saying no I don't agree with
that statement and you're holding your
line or you are turning around and you
are developing new ones or you're making
new connections and you're kind of
sitting there going oh okay maybe I can
assimilate that but I'm in a different
stage of my life or like the situation's
not right for what you're saying but
maybe I can extrapolate a piece of that
and use that in my life
>> and I I I I Know I find that that works
a lot with the way I view things. But
maybe that's the intuitive quality, you
know, because a sensor doesn't act like
that at all. I have a lot around me.
They none of them act like that. But all
the intuitives around me, whether they
realize it or not, tend to extrapolate
information and go,
>> "No, but there's a point there, and I
need to find more information, and I
feel like I need to develop whatever
that is, whether they realize they're
doing it or not."
>> Yeah. Well, dude, I I get amped that
area right there where
>> where I can notice, oh, my thinking is
differently than this or I feel strongly
about the opposing view or I feel
strongly uh about agreeing with you.
Whatever it is, I love challenging what
I think. I love like hit and play on a
podcast and you know, maybe it's just
two knucklehead comedians, but then I'm
like, man, I I am now thinking in a
different way than I thought of before I
hit play on this. I love that. That
entices me.
>> It's funny. I was watching one just the
other day and it was a funny podcast. It
was a short one, like a super short
interview podcast scenario, but neither
one of them are Christians, but they
were two different types of
non-Christians or atheist agnostic, like
they just don't believe in any sort of
God or any sort of deity thing. But
watching them, one's coming about it,
well, you know, it's community and it's
this and it's that, so it's not all that
bad. And the other one's like, nope, I'm
done. I'm out. like like kind of thing,
but they're spiritual. So, it was very
interesting listening to these two very
different viewpoints and one finally
saying, "Oh, well, I was reared
Catholic." I was like,
>> "Well, when you're browbeating in the
church, you're going to run from it." Or
anything, whether it's politics, whether
it's church, whether it's education,
whether what your home family, whatever
system and structure it is, you're going
to run.
>> Well, yeah. I mean, I I think it's a
good
>> Well, well, I mean, it kind of tells it
tells you a lot about a person. like you
can hear them going on like, "Oh, they
have this idea and here's what they
think, whatever." And then they have a
sentence like you said where they just
suddenly go, you know, "Oh, by the way,
I was raised in this way or like I grew
up in a Catholic household, whatever."
Then you can, not always, but a lot of
times you can go, "Oh, okay, that makes
sense why you feel the way you do." Like
I I I've talked about um the difference
in people who like they just blindly
trust or appeal to authority versus a
lot of like you know the you know
creative poet uh independent from a
young age type. And so like I never I
didn't have that instant trust in like
adults even, you know. And so sometimes
I'll hear people and they're going on
about all these whatever their their
beliefs or they they trust this person
who said this thing or this scientist or
this government entity whatever blah
blah blah and I'm trying to figure out
why it is like man so you heard that and
you just fully believe that and like but
that's not my experience. I hear it and
I feel like I want to challenge it. And
then you kind of hear a sentence like
that. It's like, okay, well, I grew up
in this sort of household and it was
this teaching. And not not just use it
as a broad example, not to just say like
people who are religious believe
everything they hear or something, but
um ju just like uh it's a good example
of how we all come to the different
conclusions differently in reasons why
we land on different areas, but you
know, we could we could have
conversations there and get to the point
of, oh, okay, I was raised differently
than you. I had a different experience
growing up. why I think these things.
Tell me more about why you got to how
you're where you're at, you know?
>> Well, and that I do find that's the
lynch pin. And I don't think especially
in society today,
it's intentionally reinforced to not do
that. You don't want to get to know your
neighbor. You don't want to know the the
reason, not just the why, but the reason
behind why because the rationale because
if you did, it humanizes somebody. And
we can't sew discord. We can't we can't
meddle in society, you know. We can't
then move in the shadows over here
because wait a second, Dave, pay
attention to us. We have you squabbbling
down here. And I mean that for
everything from marketing to the most
insidious of stuff that you could talk
about. But I really do think that
between social media and media media,
you know, archaic news, which is just a
bunch of pundits talking in my opinion
in today's day and age, like not a
single journalist exists anymore in my
opinion. Like you'll have the really
independent ones that are trying and
they're just putting facts out there,
but you have to s hunt and search those
people down and even then they have
their own bias.
>> I think that was the one thing that I
learned. one of my best professors, my
favorite professor ever at university.
My degree is radio, television, film,
but I their focus was independent film
and documentary film making. I didn't
want anything to do with documentary
films. Like I it didn't interest me. I
wanted to do fiction. I wanted to do
music videos. Like that's one of the
reasons I was going to school. Bring
back the modern movie musical because it
was I was started university before
Mulan Rouge existed. I graduated high
school in 2000. So, we didn't have a
modern movie musical like it died with
Eva kind of thing in the '9s. They tried
it and it didn't work. But
what's interesting is we would sit there
in her class and she sat there and said
to us, "If you don't like documentary,
think of this as an independent
filmmaking class." I was like, "Great,
fantastic." And I was like, "Thank you
for giving me another viewpoint." That
right there is the mark of a good
educator. It's not trying to browbe you
or tell you what to think. It's somebody
that goes, "Here's an alternate way to
look at something."
>> Oh, okay. Cool. Here's another tool in
your tool belt. But then she turned
around and asked us what we thought
documentaries were. And so everybody,
you know, as you do in the classroom in
your late teens and early 20s,
everybody's raising their hand. It's
National Geographic. It's it's that and
the other. And then she said, "Well, any
how-to video is a documentary. You're
documenting the process of doing
something.
You know, any feature." Then all of a
sudden I went, "Oh my gosh, all the
featurettes I love to watch on the
making of a concert, the making of a
movie, the making of theater, the making
of a behind the music behind or the
making the video on MTV. It's a docu
series. Is it partially scripted?" Yes.
But you're documenting
>> making Britney Spears toxic music video,
right? Like you're you're you're seeing
the process of how something is made.
And it changed the way I viewed it.
>> I I love that. Yo, that that's cool
though. I mean, that's so cool. A good
teacher can do that, right? Like they
can they can take something that you
think you know all about and when you're
in high school or college, you obviously
think you know everything you need to
know. Uh
anything like me anyway. Um and then Oh
man, I love that. And I'm going to reuse
your your uh term of lynch pin too
because that is another lynch pin of
just like as soon as a teacher can say
things in the correct way, you go, "Oh,
okay." And then you could suddenly you
have this whole genre basically that now
you could be totally happy about
learning more about and diving into.
>> Well, that that's I mean I could go I
could talk just for an hour about the
great educators I've had and then the
bad teachers I've had and just and how
that has shaped a lot of things because
we all know we've had bad teachers. We
all know that there's they don't like
me. Well, that's 50/50. That's
perception. But we all know that we've
at least had one teacher in our life
that did not like the cut of our jib.
>> Didn't we were too talkative in class.
We fidgeted too much. We didn't turn in
assignments on time. Like stuff that
innately is a problem. Or you would do
something
>> and they just had a chip on their
shoulder, you know? And we're human. It
it it happens. I know I've definitely
had a few teachers like that.
But even the ones that weren't a fan of
me couldn't say that I wasn't polite.
couldn't say I wasn't cordial and
congenial. Like he talks too much in
class. Like he just needs to settle down
and just stop it. But he's polite. Like
I can't just get on his case cuz he's
not like all the other little spits in
the classroom, you know? So that I mean
it's nice to know that when your parents
go in for a meeting and they're like,
"Well, you're in trouble, but you're not
in trouble because you're a little spit.
You know, you have to do turn your
homework in and you have to do the
things."
>> Yeah. you know, you're participating too
much.
>> Yeah. Wait, were you not even
participating? That's the problem.
You're just you're distracting everybody
around you because you're bored in the
classroom.
>> Yeah.
>> And that's and that was always a big
problem for me. It's like
this is too much. And I don't think the
classroom environment is good for a
student anyway. But that's a whole
different topic.
>> Well, well, did you Man, I actually kind
of do want to talk about this. What did
you Were you born Did you have ADHD?
Anything like that? Do you consider
yourself any Do you have any of those
neurode divergent traits?
>> Not to my knowledge. I was never
diagnosed with anything. Uh, the closest
thing that shares those traits is in
middle school, we all got hauled into
the cafeteria to take a test, just a
random test. They didn't tell our
parents, which, you know, that probably
went over very well. I know with my
family, you don't do that. So, welcome
to the public education system. But what
was cool about the test is I didn't know
what it was. I'll tell you what the test
is in a second. I'll bury the lead, but
I take it. I'm like, "Oh, this is easy.
Like, I don't know what's, you know,
blah blah blah blah blah." I was like,
"Oh, these are kind of different
questions. These are fun." Da da da. So,
and but what was weird was I was in the
class with everybody that was in honors
classes. So, I was in middle I was in
middle school at this point. So, I I'm
not with the honor students. I was kind
of a work smarter, not harder. Like, I
sit on the back row, don't care, you
know, kind of student. I got so burned
out in elementary school.
whole another topic. But
what's funny about it is I take this
test, I'm like, great. I'm not I don't
belong with these kiddos, but fine,
whatever. Cool. I'm not with like the
bad bad behavioral ones, the ones that
end up in in-house suspension or do the
other things, but I'm over here with
Okay, you're straight A's. Great. Cool.
Um,
ends up later, I get called by the
office over the PA to go to the library
like months later. And this the
librarian who loved me, I loved the
librarian and she loved me, handed me
this manila envelope and it was this
package. She's like, "Give this to your
parents." And I was like, "Oh, shoot.
I'm in trouble."
>> Yeah.
>> Like like, "Oh, crap.
Don't look at it." And but you're going
to take a peek. And I took a peek at it
and I was like,
>> you're in the top percentile, top five
percentile of the United States, blah
blah blah blah blah. I didn't understand
what it means. I am on like at least for
my age bracket this gifted and talented
scale. What I don't know what the tests
are called now. I don't know what they
called it back in 1990 blah blah blah.
They called it gifted and talented.
>> And so come to find out I'm like some
between spatial relations and
linguistics. I'm like off the charts on
something. But I can't even find the
packet to this day. Like I've moved, my
family's moved. And so I I've been
trying to find it. My parents keep all
of that stuff and none of us can find
it. But it was like this really
interesting thing, but being gifted and
talented shares about half of the ear
markers of ADD, ADHD. So if you don't
have somebody that knows how to
>> differentiate, they'll s you on medicine
>> just to control you in my opinion. Uh
but
>> everybody around me thought it was like
an ADD, ADHD kind of thing. But it's
like children aren't meant to sit there
for hours like you're in a sweat shop
and listen to the the work bell, you
know? I mean that's the whole thing is
structured intentionally to be like a
worker drone. So the classroom
environment, especially when you're
younger, you're meant to get up, you're
meant to move, you're meant to do these
things,
>> but you also have to structure it. I see
both sides of it. Like if if you're
actually thinking about you have to
structure it. You can't just run a muk.
Those classrooms don't work.
>> Yeah. So, it's you need to learn to sit
here for this short amount of time and
then we're all going to go do a little
field trip and go do this, clear your
mind out, and then come back. Those kind
of classrooms were the best ones for me.
So, to answer your question, I've never
been diagnosed with anything, but I'm on
some sort of wonderful special scale
that annoys teachers.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Well, I I think it's
probably different nowadays. I mean, I
don't the amount of people that are
diagnosed with that sort of thing
nowadays versus when you and I were in
school is just huge. Obviously, you
know, it's a it's a ton more. Um, I
don't know if that necessarily means
that there's more people with ADHD. I'm
sure there is. I'm sure something about
our environment or our food or our, you
know, vaccine, whatever the question is.
There's something that is changing
making us more uh susceptible to ADHD
and that sort of thing. Our phone, for
example. Oh my gosh.
>> But yeah, I man I think the core of it
is is a decent teacher with the correct
resources. You know, granted that they
have the time and they could give these
students the resources. They find like,
okay, that person doesn't do well in
this environment, but clearly they're
passionate and they're interested in
something. So, let's see if we can set
them loose on the right things. Cuz like
I can be considered someone with ADHD,
but like man, put me in front of a DJ
controller. That's a great place to have
ADHD. You know what I mean? Like I can
hyperfixate on things that pay my bills
and it's worked well for me in my life.
But in school, if I'm trying to like pay
attention and stop talking and only
they'll listen to this history from 1954
and and re remember it and repeat it,
whatever. Man, that's so boring to me.
But get me on other things, I can pay
great attention. So I'm I'm sure you
were probably in a similar boat.
>> It's I I think everybody is like if
we're interested in it, we're going to
we're going to be drawn to it. And none
of us want to sit there and read from a
book. Nobody wants to read about Ted and
Fred and how their the cat sat on the
hat and you know figure out the word
problems in math when it would be better
shape us. Who needs to know about the
red train going from Tokyo to Los
Angeles and how much time is it going to
take when it would be better for us to
learn about economics from the
perspective of you know the word problem
about work running a business. if you
have this many items and this is your
inventory and you just reshaped the word
problem, but it I was reading something
recently and it was talking about
Rockefeller and how he helped shape the
education system and that it's anybody
that's affluent or is educated has that
they get that at home. So, we
intentionally don't put it in the
education system
>> to keep people,
you know, at a certain level. I don't
know how true all of it is. I haven't
done a deep dive into it. It was just
some stuff I was reading and I was like
that doesn't surprise me because
>> that makes sense.
>> The school bell is a work whistle if you
think about when they were developing
the department of the education system
and then becoming the department of
education which has no love loss for me.
Um I
you you see how the structure and then
the bureaucratic structure mixed with it
ends up hurting students,
>> right?
>> And it hurts teachers as well because it
doesn't give them the resources. It's
the reason why the arts are defunded.
It's not because the arts aren't
helpful. It's because they're too
helpful. It's because the arts create
connective tissues in your brain. Music
is math. Math is music. rhythm, time
structure, notes, all of it. They all
sync up. You can look at all sorts of
things from woo woo theory to actual
practical music theory and they all say
the same thing. And so you'll have all
these people talking about the arts are
so important and we both are in arts
field that have a tech side and
logistics and all this, but heaven
forbid we put resources and effort into
that.
I have a whole series of thoughts about
it because it's also the type of person
that flocks to it and those people are
not always taken seriously.
>> Okay, tell me more. Tell me more.
>> In my opinion, as as what I've noticed
because I've worked a lot in as a
contractor in education. So, I've worked
with students from a little bit in the
middle school, but predominantly teenage
and 20somes like that's whether it's in
the education environment in the
institution
or outside of it. And it's the same kind
of age bracket whether it's theater or
coral or dance or tech or any of that
sort of stuff. Design
totally derailed my own train of
thought. What was I going to say? Uh you
said tell me about it.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. So we're talking about
the arts and um essentially how like you
know we have different minds and we're
kind of trained to be factory workers
essentially and that doesn't work for
everybody. Well, when it comes to the
arts, one of the big things it is, like
I said before, it's a connective tissue
to extrapolate to a lot of different
things. We literally consume art every
day. We consume it. The billboards you
watch, the structure the billboard was
built on is a form of art. Architecture
is art. The house or the apartment
you're sitting in, you know, the things
that you take for granted, the freaking
carpet, like there's art in everything.
It's just some fields are more logistic
and some fields aren't. One of the
problem with the education system is
that it's bureaucratic
and bureaucracy. A lot of times sensors
gravitate towards bureaucracy, not
necessarily intuitives. Sensors aren't
always artists. You'll find the
predominant amount of people that are
intuitive. It's going to be a higher
amount of intuitives in the arts than
you are going to find sensors
full and well. and being reared by a
sensor, a very strong sensor. It's
interesting how she can appreciate art
very, very much so, but doesn't feel
artistic in her own right. So, and I'm
kind of the opposite where it's like my
feelings are intuitions. They're not
always emotional. Like I don't have that
feel or emotional reaction to thing.
So being more being more on the thinker
scale, it's interesting when I get
around the performing arts and you're
around a lot of willowy feelers and all
this sort of stuff. You just start
going, "Okay, I I'm I really need you.
You're at a 10. I need you at a two.
I'll take a four or a five kind of
thing." And that's not to denigrate
anybody. It's just to say
>> we all process things differently and
our thresholds are different. and
intuitive feelers really tend to go
towards the performing arts
specifically.
>> And so in tech, you'll get a lot more
sensors and you'll get a lot more people
that would be an engineer, but they have
an artistic streak or they want to be
involved in something creative. And so
you'll end up with students or adults
that are creating these amazing sets,
doing this great lighting design, doing
running audio, you know, editors, you
know, it's it's all interchanges. I
don't know if I completely answered what
you where you were wanting to go.
>> No, pretty much. Yeah. No, I'll I'll
poke and produce towards things I I
think are interesting. Actually, what I
would like to do, um, just curious if
anybody listening, if they have not, um,
you know, gone the Myerbriggs route and
explored their own personalities. For
one, hey, check it out. I definitely
encourage everybody 16
personalities.com. I think that's the
one that I like. Um, could you tell me
the difference between like a a sensor
and and a feeler? Um,
>> feeler or sensor and an intuitive?
>> Sensor and intuitive. Yeah. In your
definition, it's fine. You don't have
to.
>> Yeah. Do you want me to pull up the
clinical one?
>> No. No. Yeah. Whatever you have to say
about it is good. Basically, I just I
just go with the fact that a sensor is
someone that lets kind of the external
world dictate the way that they are
going to interpret their information.
Whereas an intuitive, you run it through
your own funnel and then you output the
data. So my reaction is going to be I
collect everything around me and then
every time I make a bad decision I I
used to go to the site and actually test
just a bridge test when things keep
going wrong and just like it's bad and
things haven't been going right. I'll
I'll usually test slightly more sensor
like I it'll ping over to the sensor.
I'm like because you're not listening to
yourself. you're you're not listening to
what's innate to you or to me
personally. So, which is redundant to
say, but you know what I mean. Uh so,
I've noticed that where it's like, okay,
when I make bad decisions, it's this
happened, so that happens, so I need to
do this. You don't take that beat and
run it through your own funnel. You're
you're reacting as opposed to absorbing,
re reinterpreting, and then not putting
the data. It doesn't work for everybody.
I I have a lot of sensor. I shouldn't
say a lot. I'm 50/50 probably with
sensors around me and intuitives, but I
will tell you it causes conflict when
you have a strong sensor and a strong
intuitive and they're trying to
communicate with each other. You can say
the exact same thing.
>> Yeah.
>> And one's coming at it from the front
door and one's coming at it from the
skylight. And neither one of you are
going to meet until you can take a beat
and take a breath and go, "Hold on. How
is this person?
I think we're saying the same thing.
>> Yeah. Yeah. How are we saying that? What
are we saying?
>> Yeah.
>> But but if it's in the point where
you're getting heated, it Oh my gosh.
And that can be in anything from your
chores to political nonsense to, you
know, religious doctrine to just
anything.
But I I think you have to take the beat.
And as I've grown older, I've learned
how to kind of go, oh, I'll fire back.
Most people don't nowadays people don't
don't see that side of me until they
meet the side of me and then they're
like that came out of nowhere. It's like
no it didn't come out of nowhere. I was
just very I've learned to be very
patient and go
>> okay there's so many things you have to
do in a day. This is not the battle that
I Okay, this is the battle that I'm
going to have to fight. Okay, cool. I'm
down. Let's go. You want to go? We can
go.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I mean that that is how it
goes. you do have to you start to learn
especially if you're able to kind of
take that that step back that meta
perspective of okay what's going on in
this situation cuz so often we're you
know we're trying to fight it from being
within it like we're our head's deep in
the dang thing and we're like having the
arguments and we're disagreeing or
whatever a lot of times you got to you
know pull your head out of your butt or
whatever this this example I'm putting
here uh I'll save my inappropriate jokes
um so basically just like pull yourself
out of it and and observe it from a
distance right and then you can kind of
have Uh um you could you could see where
you're where you're butting heads and
where you're both all you just you're
trying to overall accomplish the same
thing with this other person, but you
can kind of go, okay, is it worth me
taking my energy to argue this? If this
were is this worth me letting go for a
while and then we reapproach it? Do I
need to let them cool off and me cool
off and then we realize, hey, we're on
the same page. We're talking about the
same thing. So, where where in your life
has you've had so many different
experiences, so many, you know, in the
creative world for sure, but all of your
other expertise um
how did you start to find where you
noticed, okay, my reactions, me arguing
with this person isn't helpful. Me
bumping heads with this type of person
seems to keep happening. Um because what
I what I want to ask, Curtis, is kind of
like maybe there's people listening who
they notice they're bumping heads with
everybody. They were they're work with
creatives. Maybe they are the creative,
maybe they're not the creative, but they
noticed that there's a way that they
could better, more amicably communicate.
I think that's something that definitely
one of the a lot of the
>> main reason I want to get you on there.
One of the main reasons um
>> you're an excellent communicator. It's
something that I I noticed right off the
bat. I mean, all of us working together,
even our casual conversations, we just
talk forever and you communicate so
well. Um, and I think it's a superpower
and a lot of people, um, there's a lot
of people who probably work with you and
will work alongside you or see you and
your ability to be so charismatically
communicative is admirable. So, I'm sure
there's other people who are like, man,
I'd love to be as charismatic and
communicative as Curtis, how would I get
there? So, I'm just wondering if there
was a maybe an opening for you or maybe
how you used to do things versus how you
do them now. How could you speak to
those people who want to communicate
better?
It's it's a series of things. It isn't
just one,
>> right?
>> We'll start with I'm just naturally a
articulate,
very gifted in that. That is a genetic
innate thing that got reinforced.
>> My grandmother and my mother were very
big on English. They were very big on
language and speaking clearly and
concisely. I'm an officer's child and my
father also ran joint ventures,
international joint ventures later in
life. So I'm, you know, an executive's
child slash an officer's child. So you
have to present a specific way as it is.
So now now you have this kind of waspy
thing going on and then you have this,
oh, you do naturally speak. I spoke
early for a girl like as in
developmentally. I was speaking early. I
walked early. I like I only crawled to
climb up onto something to become
bipedal. I didn't do the ooching stuff.
I didn't do I didn't go through the
normal steps. Same thing with talking. I
started a little bit of babbling my
mother says and then you had full words
and then it was full phrases. It was
never why. It was for what reason as a
toddler. Like what toddler says for what
reason? This one. But the funny but the
funny thing about that is I must have
keyed into something being around adults
all of the time in that there's a
rationale and a reason or it was the
type of adults I was around. My mother
had as an educator defed as well as
English. So being articulate would have
obviously been reinforced. She would
notice if there was something wrong with
a speech pattern or you're congested or
you can't hear something and we need to
get in and see if there's something
wrong with your ears or there's
something going on. She just
saw it almost immediately as soon as
speech patterns but I had it. So I don't
know that's that's where that nature
nurture thing is. It's genetic 100%.
>> But it got nurtured. So So there's that.
I was very loquacious and very obviously
and very u engaging when I was a child.
Never met a stranger kind of thing but
didn't trust certain people like like wy
at an early age and then school just
kind of beat it out of me like I became
way way more insular. You know when you
don't really have friends in school and
you're just kind of working your way
through it. the trying to communicate on
that level with people it becomes
difficult. So that's where the first
major hiccup in the journey is. I could
communicate with an adult like that no
problem. And I had this immense frame of
reference where I could talk to somebody
and they'd be like how do you know about
laughing? How do you know like this
episode of a show that I watched when I
was a tween or a teen kind of thing and
you're in 1980 whatever early 1990s kind
of thing. I'm like because I was allowed
to watch it. You know, Nick at Night
existed and
>> Exactly. And I think that's something
>> we can I I do want to hit that as a
point later about exposure to things and
this younger generation versus my
generation and what I've noticed
throughout the years.
>> Yeah, definitely. Please.
>> But in regards to communication, I'm
talking way too much. But to get to the
point is that I would then start having
hiccups with my own peers because I was
anac an anacronism in my own time.
>> Yeah.
>> I love the Beach Boys.
who as a a 5-year-old, an 8-year-old in
1980, whatever, Texas, loves the Beach
Boys, loves um Buddy Holly and the
Crickets, Frankie Valley and the Four
Seasons, Jan and Dean, uh the Chapons,
the Charels, any of the Mottown music,
any of the Phil Spectre, the Brill
Building pop music. I It was the first
music that I found that was mine, which
was weird because I had Michael Jackson.
We had the original thriller LP. That's
what got me to sleep as a toddler. You
know, I wasn't stuck listening to
Lullabis. I was listening to like pop
rock music curated, of course, but you
know, I had the Madonna. I had the
Michaels, but then I'd found this
section of music. My peers weren't
listening to that,
>> right?
>> They were listening to Cooko because
that had come out from the cocktail
soundtrack, but they So, I didn't have a
shortorthhand with my own peers, but I
had a short hand with adults.
So that took a long time to develop
with with my own peers. It was just
frustrating. It just never worked.
>> Yeah.
>> But it but it wasn't difficult to
communicate. It was just we had two
completely different sets of interests
and I was a social paria. So when when
you're those two things, you just kind
of you do you. You learn to do you and
you just move forward.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I mean, and I think it's
something to be said about if if the
students in other classmates around you
are just not into the same things you're
into or they're not really talking about
things that interest you, I could see
that being like, you know, you you had a
kind of an
a taste for intellectualism almost like
you almost wanted wanted to have
conversations maybe that were um a
little bit different than the people
around you could potentially provide.
>> I I would agree with that assessment.
Like I I think
what's interesting is you only know what
you know. The rest is learning.
>> So at any given stage, especially when
you're younger, you're still developing.
Like your your prefrontal cortex lobe is
not developed until approximately 25
years of age. So boy, we all thought we
knew a lot as teenagers, didn't we? And
I consider a 20-year-old a teenager. You
know what I mean? Like, you know, just
because you're 18 and you're magically
an adult legally, you're not
>> you're no more an adult than you were at
17, but it's like calling a 17-year-old
a child. You're not a child. You know
right from wrong.
>> Yeah.
>> Like like you know what I mean? Like for
the most part,
>> 000 whatever percent of the people that
don't know it, blah blah blah blah blah.
Like
>> but in all seriousness, like you you
know certain things by that point. So,
it's that's when things got better was
finally getting to a being a teenager
and I'd found friends outside of school
that were older. I would I would have be
friends with people that were my age and
then I would gravitate towards their
older siblings.
>> Sure. I would I would then I just met
this friend group at the local
university
just one of them happened to work at
Blockbuster Video and I was always in
there and we struck up a conversation
and I was basically by my junior senior
year I was living a dual life during the
day I was a high school student and some
weekends and then some evenings and some
weekends I was hanging out with these
college friends and they weren't people
that I with whom I went to school so I
didn't know them all the way through. It
was the first true group of friends that
I made of my own accord and we could
talk about different things. They were
being educated at a higher level and at
a different rate and had more exposure
to different topics or a more in-depth
exposure to topics. So it it
automatically filled
I guess what was lacking in a lower
educational environment that has a lot
of surface or a lot of when you're in a
religious area and it's a very specific
group of people there's a lot of what's
the word I want to use
not stigma but
castigation
>> like like you you're bad there's
something wrong with you if you don't go
to our church or if you don't believe
this thing. And I'm like, there's so
many denominations, dude. We're all
Christians here. Or if you're not
Christian, Judeo-Christian or, you know,
whatever, because of where we were in
Texas.
>> Yeah.
>> Come on. Like, take a take a beat, take
a pill. It's not It's deep, but not that
deep. You know what I mean? You're a
child. I'm a child. Like, let's move on
with our lives here.
>> Yeah. I mean, and to put someone in a
whole box of like, oh, he doesn't he
didn't say yes to that one sentence that
we really feel good about when he says
yes. So, let's not invite him over for
dinner like that. Like, come on. Like,
how about just expand yourself and talk
with the person? He might teach us
something you don't even know.
>> What's funny about that is but I've done
it myself and not realized I've done it
to people. Yeah, you and that I think is
the next part of communication is
realizing that you will inevitably do
the very thing that you're
being you're upset that somebody else is
doing. You're going to do it. We're
human. You know, it's just natural to
want to be tribal. I just naturally
happen to be a lone wolf, but it's
natural to want to cluster off and be a
part of the group and oh, this is a fun
crowd. I want to be Oh, I really don't
want to be over here. Or, oh, yeah, I
really do. And do they accept me? Do
they not accept me? Yeah.
>> As I got through university, I started
realizing that the that quotient I have
for big picture thinking, not everybody
had. And people can't then zero in on
that minute detail. Most people live in
the midplane.
>> Yeah.
>> Of of observation. So when you're
leaping between you can't see the bigger
picture like five steps down the line,
but I'm so focused on this minute detail
over here, you've just missed a whole
bunch that everybody else is like,
>> "Duh."
>> Yeah.
>> So it's finding that way to fill that
gap and ask someone for that
information. So that requires listening.
>> Yeah.
>> So I I would say that the next part of
it, you're probably going to have to
chop all of this up for it to make
sense.
>> Yeah. It's decently cohesive. It's fine.
Yeah. or or to streamline it. But
listening, the biggest thing I can say
about communication is listening. Most
people don't listen. They hear you hear
what I'm saying.
>> You're not listening to the words that I
am using. And words have meaning. Yes.
Because we give it to them. And in
today's day and age, people play fast
and loose with the meanings of words. I
understand that there's an etmology of
language, but it has a root. As archaic
as it may be
>> to to raise someone is not to rear
someone.
You raised chicken and cattle. You rear
children. But we colloquially use raise
in lie of rear. It's two different
things. My mother always said you were
reared not raised.
You know, it's it's it's that semantic.
>> That's great. Yeah, that's they are
important details. They are, but if
you're not taught those details and
where did I where was I taught those
details? At home, not in the education
system.
>> So, right there there's a thing because
even the best educators have to follow
curriculum,
>> right?
>> And curriculum is going to dictate a
lot. The best teachers I ever had,
>> jog on. Like they they did their own
thing
>> within the very loose framework of it.
But I I'll get to that later because I
would love to talk about some of the
best things that teachers have ever
done.
>> Yeah.
>> In my life. But for communication, so
it's for me it's been to sum it up. It's
natural.
I there's a lot of ingrained just traits
that I have. I My parents were very
influential in making sure to reinforce
it. realizing that you had to learn by
listening.
>> Mhm.
>> Because if you don't listen to what the
other person is saying, you're not going
to respond. The the response is going to
be a different response.
I don't know how better to explain it.
If I half listened to you, I I I'm not
understanding what you're asking or what
you're saying to me.
>> Well,
>> and
>> go ahead. Go ahead. Well, and one the
last thing I was going to say is I then
learned through a series during my work
life of I used to be very very direct
like like that that kind of tur short
because that's in my work life and
everything else. You get yelled at if
you screw something up like let's say
we're working together on a show again.
Okay. It'll probably happen.
>> Yeah.
>> And you accidentally cue something
incorrectly. How many times have you
heard over the clearcom somebody getting
ripped a new one?
>> You know what I mean? How many times in
just oneonone you did and it's and it's
just like it is heated and you're being
browbeating and people in today's day
and age like oh it's so toxic.
>> Some of the best things that I ever
learned were from somebody just ripping
me a new one at 14 years of age
>> because it's direct and it's heated. It
puts enough fear into you that you go I
don't fear of consequence not fear of
the person.
like I don't ever want to do that again.
I have a whole story about that. But it
also made sure that I started realizing
I wasn't getting with this younger
generation. And when I say younger, I
mean like the youngest of millennials
and younger as I would work with them
when I would say, well, you know,
the first act isn't going very well. You
know what I mean? I noticed that this
this isn't this. You know, go fix it and
come back. Because that's how I was
taught. you screwed up. Go fix it. Come
back. You're not going to get attab boy.
You're not going to get all these extra
things. What ended up happening was the
second act tanked and went even worse.
>> Oh wow.
>> Because you hurt someone took it
personally.
And it's like, well, firstly, you should
still be backstage and you shouldn't
have come out into the house to go talk
to friends and family. Like the show is
still going on even through
intermission. Like let's let's talk
about professionalism here, but clearly
no one taught that to you.
So that's but being that direct and too
honest which sometimes can almost be a
sensor trait where it's like well you
just need to fix it and I'll give you
the tools to fix it but you just need to
do it. You now have to create the
compliment sandwich. I appreciate the
work that you're doing blah blah blah
blah blah. Insert the light version of
how you need to fix it. Thank you so
much. Have a nice day. And you have to
do this sandwiching.
And it's been pervasive for
how old am I?
Probably over 15 years now. It's I've
had to do this technique for over 15
years now. I don't feel like I should
have to, but it works. It takes a little
more time out of my day. Someone doesn't
feel,
you know, doesn't feel some kind of way.
They don't get in their feelings from
it. And really, it's elicited a better
response. So, like this year more than
ever, I've had a lot of people comment
about I'm always smiling when I'm on a
project and I'm working. I don't know
why. Like, and it's not a grim. It's
like it's a genuine smile. And I'm like,
"Huh, I didn't realize I was doing
that." Like, I I just didn't realize it.
But it's getting into this different
mindset. It's say, "I'm not paid to have
a bad attitude.
>> I'm not paid to come in here and tell
someone off. There's another way to do
things." Two things can be true at once.
There are multiple ways to do them. It's
finding an extra tool for your tool belt
going, "Oh, that didn't elicit the
response that I wanted. Let me try this
technique with somebody. Let me try that
technique with somebody." I mean, I
think that's why I gravitated that first
year we worked together and I was like,
"Oh, I like Jacob." Like, like love it.
Well, no, because you got it like you
you were picking up on things before I
even said them. I was like, "Oh, he's he
has to be an intuitive." Like there's
there's no other way this would work the
way it does because you were like,
"Well, I saw that you there were these
audio cues and you were missing
something, so I just pulled a bunch of
stuff for you that was kind of in the
vein of it." You went ahead of what you
should have to do and you preempted
something.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> But we we were able to communicate and I
would say with half of the way we talk
with each other on site, they're almost
half sentences sometimes.
>> For sure. Yeah. Because because we're on
the same page, it's like, "Okay, cool.
Go go go go go go."
>> Yeah.
>> I don't know. Does that help anything?
Does that
>> No. No. It absolutely does. Well, okay.
So, I think that something that we're
both able to do is like for one, like
nothing's personal. Like if even if
you're like, "That song sucks. I don't
want it new." Like, done. Cool. Say
less. It's not personal. It's not like
my taste in music sucks and you like are
insulting me. But I I think especially
in live events, something that is very
useful and helps with communication
between creatives is you and I both know
we have an end goal. Like this door
opens at 6:30 p.m. And like we know that
we have high expectations. At a certain
point at 400 p.m. Sometimes we have to
start lowering our expectations because
it's like, do I have time to make this
happen in those two? Whatever. But not
that we're trying to lessen the impact
of the show. We're all still on board
for having the best show possible. like
we're here to do this thing and like we
know from experience when we do it well
it's impressive. We're proud of it. The
audience has a wonderful moving
experience. Like that's the juice, man.
We want to do that. So if we're able to
get kind of on the same vibe of, hey
man, we're trying to make a good show
here. So if you can say something and
halfway through it I'm like I get what
you're talking about. Say less. I got
you. We're we're both here to have a
great show. We're both here to make an
experience for these people who are uh
you know involved whether they're in the
show or they're watching it. the work
and production. We're all in this to
like have a a good experience of working
a show, a good experience of seeing the
show, blah blah blah. Um, yeah. And so
if I can remove my I think a lot of
times our lack of communication
sometimes is
I mean looking at me when I was younger
is like I would keep I would be offended
by stuff. So people would say things and
I would well I I spent forever I spent
so much time on this like and you don't
you clearly don't even listen to what
I'm trying to do and and blah blah blah.
It's like no he There's many reasons why
this person said what they said. The
door's open at this time. We got to get
to work, you know? So, it's not about my
feelings. It's not about me finding
something that feels really good for me.
Like, these people in the audience, they
don't care about like how I feel about
the song, you know? It's it's a a
general cohesive thing. So, um yeah, I
think listening part of part of being a
good listener is not taking things
personally, too. I think that's a that's
an important part of it. Yeah,
>> that that's something that I've learned
in business. I don't do it all of the
time, but I have no problem saying this
is these are my thoughts. You've hired
me or an opinion. These are my thoughts
on it. I don't agree I want it this way.
Okay, fine. I still don't agree with
you. I think this is what's going to
come out of it, but you're paying me.
It's not my It's not my thing. If you
like what I produce, as long as you like
what I give you at the end of the day,
it's not about me.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> And I I don't have to deal with that
often. I think I had to deal with that
when I was younger.
Now I'm way more in tune with the people
I'm around.
>> Like it's it's I don't know. Once you
finally lynch pin in and link in and you
get there with somebody, you're like,
"Got it. I I know what we're doing
here." You know, it may take a couple of
steps to get there. And that's the music
side or that's a design side or that's a
oh, you're asking me to run the show
this way.
Okay, hold on. I'm going to have to take
a few minutes to like recalibrate what
I'm doing and and move my head my head
space over to this over here.
>> Y
>> speaking of that, asking about
communication because I have done
everything from staging and choreography
and this this more movementbased
dialogue based artistic style and then
you move over to design and technology
and you know obviously you met me as
what working backstage.
What would how would you even
>> Yeah. What are all your titles when when
I'm working with you? What are your
plethora of titles?
>> Well, the the actual titles are music
and show music and staging director.
>> Okay.
>> So, it's like basically music director
and staging director. They're two
completely different things, but because
I have a major background in making sure
that performers get where they need to
be and do what they need to do on stage
and
>> yeah,
>> formations and dance and movement and
all of that, there's that, but that's
the on-site component of it. The offsite
is periodic opinions on things, you
know, as anybody would have, but you're
not going to get, oh, well, I said this
should happen with this outfit, so
you're going to get like that's not a
credit. That's a, okay, you're a part of
the team. I think that's something that
people get twisted. They think that just
because they had an opinion on one
thing,
>> they should have a loftier title or
something else. And I was there when I
was younger. It's it's that you're
excited and got to tamper that down a
little bit and realize, no, you're part
of the team. You were hired to do this.
This is the next part of it. And the
pre-production stuff, a lot of it is
music related and it's music editing and
it's making sure that there's a not just
a sound bed, but it's cohesive
>> and it's more of a soundtrack. This
year, I really went in and said, "Hey, I
want to make this more like a
soundsscape and a soundtrack, which is
why the day before the show, we're
sitting there, oh, I have these tracks
now with these
>> with all these tracks." And no, we need
to add stuff to them. We we need to give
it more body. We need to make it
atmospheric now whether that's with
music or sound effects and it's just a
last minute kind of and you have on on
do your listeners know specifically all
the different tiers of what you do?
>> Probably not. No, I don't know what they
know.
>> Well, because it's one of those things
where when we're working together,
you're audio, too. So, for anybody that
doesn't know live production, there's
there's your lead and then there's the
second person and it can mean a bunch of
different things. So, I'm handing over
all my music to you
>> and or somebody else is handing the
music that I've handed over to you and
then we're communicating on how it's
supposed to play and when it's supposed
to play and oh crud. And you're you do
an amazing job looping looping looping
looping. And just to kind of round that
out, that's something
with communication is you have to
experience a lot of things first.
>> Yeah. and then you can articulate what
it is that you experienced. But if I
were to try and tell you what that show
is that we work off, okay? If I'm going
to explain it to you, I would say
it's a charity dinner. It's a fashion
show,
but it's actually think of it set up
like a concert,
>> right?
>> Like the the way the staging happens,
the way you would run things is more
like a pop concert or a concert tour. It
just happens to have theater elements in
it. This happens to have a lot of music.
It has microphones. Sometimes we have
live music. Every year is going to be
different. But I would think of it more
like a concert
>> and a ballroom or an arena, a very small
arena size.
>> Don't think of it like a normal fashion
show. Don't think of it normally like a
normal awards dinner. Don't think of it,
it's not an industrial. Do not think of
it at all like an industrial. And I
think that's a learning curve people
have when they walk into that show
specifically because to me it's more of
a concert. I don't know if you would
agree,
>> but I'm I'm almost tempted. I I think
it's a stretch of the word, misuse of
the word, but variety show almost. It's
not a variety show, but I mean like
dude, there's a full symphony, there's a
choir, there's bands, there's musicians,
there's like there how many models are
involved in like one year, would you
say?
>> It's kind of
>> Oh god, it depends on it depends on the
year because I I don't know how many
were this year cuz that I'm not on that
side of it. So I don't I I think this
year because they had it they only
duplicated a few of them.
>> So I would over 50
>> for sure over 50
>> easily over 50. So 50 to 100 like
depending on the year. Sometimes the
show's super duper big and you have all
these extra scenes because I've done
that specific show off and on since
2011.
>> Yeah.
>> So this was either year 10 or 11 of me
being on site doing the show
>> and then Yeah. Well, into and so I I'll
just say for anybody listening, if
you're wondering what we're talking
about, um there will be links in in down
below. We're talking about DIFFA, um a
fashion show that we both worked. This
that's where Curtis and I originally got
connected and started vibing with. So,
um they can definitely check that out.
I'll include Keep in mind, Curtis, there
will be links to all your stuff and all
that. They'll have a bio already. U we
we'll cover more of your bio as we
continue to continue to just casually
talk on, but uh there will be all that
info below. So, if you want to know more
about what we're kind of talking about
specifically, listener,
>> check out below. What I do want to ask
you, Curtis, um we were talking about
communication.
>> We've been talking about um how
essentially like communication is
something that it seemed that you
learned that you actually had as a
skill. Like I'm not sure if there was a
time in your life where you kind of were
able to step back and go, okay, I'm
clearly good at this communication thing
and a lot of other people aren't as
much. Um I I don't know if you had any
situations like that, but I do think
that
you you've mentioned kind of our younger
generation, you know, people who are
>> I I I want to help out people who aren't
as natural communicators, right? I I
want to speak with them. Um I so taking
in what you've experienced by just
working with people that are younger
than you, working with people with
different mindsets. Um definitely in the
creative world, but even just kind of
like the more logistic sides of our
business, the technical sides of our
business, which um there's a lot of
creatives, but there is a lot of more
structure in in other sides of our of
our world. So what what's something that
you see in the world of communication
that maybe people could do better? Maybe
they're making the same mistakes. Um
maybe they're making assumptions.
What what's kind of like some
communication advice that comes to mind?
I suppose for our younger people,
>> it's always listening. Like I will
always go back to listening because
learning that if you're not getting the
result you want from something, you it
is incumbent upon you as the person
communicating the information to
communicate the information.
You may have said it once one way.
Great. The other person may not be
receiving it right. They're not getting
it. So that means there's something
there's a disconnect there. So now you
need another tool in your tool belt to
say, "Okay, the person doesn't learn
that way or the person doesn't isn't
processing what I'm saying. I need to
rephrase this." I think a big problem is
people start getting louder
instead of rephrasing. people push and
be like, "No, it's this kind of thing or
they become more stringent and
stridident as opposed to, okay, hold on,
let me explain it differently." I don't
think because I've also had this
situation where I don't think you're
understanding why I'm saying somebody
gets offended or whatever. No, no, no,
no. It's it's not about offending
anything. It's I don't think I'm
communicating it to you effectively. Let
me try and rephrase this because I think
I'm the one doing it. Sometimes you have
to take it on yourself.
>> I think a lot of times in communication
you think just because you said
something somebody understood what you
said
>> and it's it's incumbent upon both people
to to sit there and if you don't
understand it part of that communication
is asking the follow-up question.
You have to turn around and go, "Okay, I
don't know if I really understand what
you mean by what you say. Mhm.
>> This is this is what I this is what I
extrapolated or this is what I think you
said. Is this what you said? Is this or
do you mean this by what you say? And
then they can volley back. It's just lob
and volley. They can go yes but no. What
I mean is da da da da da. Oh, it's order
of operations is the first place where
you're going to get twisted with
somebody,
>> right?
>> Because where what I think should go
first is not what you think should go
first. And it may not be what either one
of us think should go first. It's what
needs to go first.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> So, it's it's the thing that I always
had a problem with in mathematics.
I would jump steps. I was really bad.
Especially when we got to algebra. I
would skip over things. I wouldn't
>> like show your steps. You're like, I
don't know how I got there. I got the
answer though.
>> I literally I had a calculus professor,
business calculus at university and I
was doing so poorly in the class. It was
oh gosh it was 911 time period like it
was it was September and and I took my
first test and I bombed it. I bombed it
and I was like how did I do like what
because there a lot more word problems
it's calculus I you know all these
things. So I went to the professor. The
first thing I always say is if you have
a question, you immediately go talk to
take that time. A good one will take the
time to work with you if they have it.
Just don't waste their time,
>> right?
>> Like that's a big thing. I went to him
because I was like, but I some of these
answers are correct. I think he
literally because he had an adjunct or
somebody grade everything as you would.
He looked through it and he went through
every single problem. I went from a D to
a B on that one test because he saw
where I got off in my work. He would he
would go correct correct correct. That's
off. Why did they count it off? You got
the answer correct. Or you got off
track. Yeah. No, you totally bomb. No, I
can't give you anything for this
question or you know what I mean for
this problem. But then he turned around
and go, "How did you?" He looked at me
one time during that session and went,
"How did you get back on track?"
>> Like, "How did you like I don't know.
With math, my brain will just do some
things."
>> Dude, I resonate with this so much. I I
would skip steps and then I'd be
confused and frustrated that the teacher
would say, "Well, you didn't do it the
way that we're telling you to do it."
I'm like, "But you you're telling me an
end goal and to get to the end goal and
I got to the end goal. I I'm not
understanding what's wrong with the way
that I did it." you know,
>> it's because they were never told how to
explain that to students. They don't
teach that in education, I don't think,
or at least in the way that I would
interpret it in in that the we do these
steps this way for a very specific
reason. There there's a reason, there's
a rhyme, there's a rationale.
Okay, cool. If you explain it to me like
that, I will then ask, well, what's the
reason, the rhyme, the rationale? But
most people won't. But you have people
that just naturally are followers that
will say, "Okay, you told me to do it
this way. I'll do it this way." Or they
understand it. They don't they don't
need you to explain it.
>> They see the steps right in front of
them. Whereas I'm more of a for what
reason? Why are we doing it this way?
That's one of the things that I found
communication wise in work, people just
will bark things at you and tell you,
"Do it this way. Do it this way." And it
really tamps down morale.
>> Yeah.
>> But you don't always have time to
explain things to people there. That's
something that I would say to anybody
that's younger or anybody that is older
that still gets frustrated and feels
like they're beating their head against
a wall,
especially with big projects, whether
that's in a retail store environment
because I have a lot of sales
background. Obviously, I do a lot of
different types of shows and I've worked
with teams and competitions and all
sorts of stuff.
There's a lot of logistics involved and
I don't have time to explain the
logistic steps. One of the best
producers I've worked with said,
I'd suggested something one of the first
times that we worked with her and she
goes, "Thank you very much, but we don't
do it that way, but you may do it that
way in one of your other events.
It could sound dismissive. It could
sound demeaning or it could be the way I
took it which was oh
okay there's another way to do things
and maybe I can utilize this let me let
me watch how this happens and why we do
it this way and then later when the
person had time I went to the producer
and said would you explain to me why
y'all y'all do it this way I see it in
real time that it works why like what's
what's the reason behind it because
clearly you've tried it before that way
doesn't work. So when I try to
communicate, I don't always I'm not
always great about it, but it's like
I'll explain to you later the why, but
for right now, it just doesn't work
because of XYZ.
>> So let's move on to the we but we got to
keep moving with this, right?
>> Thank you. Come find me later. And if
you really want to know and I'll explain
it to you and I'm willing to take that
extra time. I'm not getting paid for it.
I'm not getting any The only thing I'm
getting out of it is making sure that
somebody doesn't walk away feeling like
they were dissed and dismissed because I
never want that.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> Kind of thing.
>> So, so it's taking that extra time if
you can manage it and learning to say
there's another way to do things and
there's a reason why we don't do it that
way or whatever.
>> Yeah. I think it's actually pretty
powerful what you said about like making
it clear to them that you're willing and
would love to explain to them later
because in our world of live events
sometimes sometimes it is a bit more
direct like I said you know we start
unloading and that's an hourglass tipped
over that sand is pouring the doors open
at the same time you know so a lot of
times we do get more short and precise
in the way we communicate um I've
actually that makes me think um it's
it's funny coming off of right at this
convers you know we're mentioning this
conversation about math and like hey
just do do it this way and like they
always don't know how to explain it to
you that way and you're like I I came up
with the right answer blah blah blah I
don't know why you want me to do it this
way but there is a moment for sure and I
see it with young people where you do
need to kind of just at least in that
moment blindly trust the person who's
telling you to do it a certain way so
like especially in live events
so so I know just an example of um in in
my world so
>> I just had uh the supervisor for a show
We were just running um Dan and Sheay
was the artist that had those
>> and um essentially there was a person on
a forklift who was doing things in a a
way that isn't the proper way to do
them. They don't have the view of
everything that you know essentially the
the supervisor knows more information
about that show overall than the person
driving the forklift. That's just a true
fact. like he has the advance, he has
the diagrams, he's been having email
conversation, he's in contact with all
the leads. He just knows more than the
person who's, you know, in the narrow
forklift. He's telling the person, "Hey,
we got to do it this way. We need it
this way right now." Basically
>> turns into an argument. The person is
like, "Well, no, I'm doing it this way.
Here's why." Blah, blah, blah. Cool. I
get that you're going to do it that way.
And the forklift, but right now, I need
you to do it this way. And in that
moment, there's other people listening.
There's clients around. There's maybe an
artist around, whatever. There's there's
the supervisor up top who knows a lot
more info about the show as a whole does
not have time and it's not the most
important thing in that high intensity
moment where it's like a forklift jammed
and people are waiting. It's not the
time to explain to you why we can't do
it your way. You need to trust the
person who's in that authoritarative
position authoritative position. I don't
love that word authoritative, but in in
that position of they you got to admit
they know more than you and trust them.
They're saying, "Hey, do it this it's
not the way you're going to do it. And
then later on, they're going to explain,
they're happily going to explain to you,
hey man, the reason why I didn't want
you to drive the forklift this way in
that manner was because over my right
shoulder, that guy watching me, he works
with OSHA or he, you know, there's some
reason that you aren't privy to in that
moment why you're being asked to do it
in a certain way. And so a lot of times
something I I'm always learning is
um to trust that person to to like, hey,
there's a reason why that why that
individual is telling me um why we need
to have it done in this way. And I
noticed in their voice, in their vocal
tone, they were being more direct than
they normally are. They're being kind of
quick. He seemed a little bit shorter
with me. He usually explains things
really detailed to me. I've got to go.
If I'm the forklift driver in that
situation, I've got to go, man. must
trust this individual's reasoning why
he's telling me to do it and just do it
the way he says and then like you said
have that conversation on the back end
of hey I know that I was kind of short
with you I know I was kind of direct
with you that isn't the way that you
want to do it I do trust your skills as
a forklift driver I'm not trying to
insult you as you know you have wisdom
that you're bringing to this table but
all that to say like there's moments
especially with a live show where you
just got to trust that person they're
telling you what's up and then having
that openness of I would love to explain
it to you on the back end. I don't have
time for right now. Please, before you
leave today, let's have this quick
combo. I want to I would love to explain
to you why I did it the way I did it and
told you the way to do it the way I told
you to do it, but right now you got to,
you know, do it this way. So, I all all
that rambling for that story on um just
just to agree like
it's huge to just trust that person in
that moment. Trust that they are great
at what they do. You know, they're good
at what they do. You know, they're they
have a great decision. They haven't let
you down before. listen to them. Do it
the way they solve the math problem in
the way they told you to solve it in
this moment. Later on, we're going to
have the conversation. So, yeah. I don't
know if you resonate with that.
>> Well, what's funny is you made me think
of something else that those of us that
have an artistic side like designers,
editors, people that have or creators,
but are also will get contracted to do a
task.
This is where I learned to stop getting
it twisted a long time ago.
If I'm hired for a mix that I've already
made, you're buying my mix. You're
buying my edit. You're buying my this.
You're buying my art in that situation.
If I've hired you to do a job, I'm
hiring you for your skill set, not your
art.
>> And we get that twisted so easily in the
arts, any sort of I shouldn't call it
the arts, in any creative field. And
that's where you start getting, for lack
of a better turn of phrase, but hurt.
Like that's when you start getting
Sally and Sammy sensitive because it's
like, "Yeah, but it's my art." It's
like, "No, you're editing music for a
freaking show. I need music that's
enjoyable for the show. If I want you to
shorten it, I need you to shorten it."
The best one of the best producers that
I've worked with over the years will
send me emails. These are the songs I
want to use. Fantastic. I need I don't
like this intro. I need you to get out
of this and into the this the lyrics
really quickly or I don't like the
lyrics but I love the intro. So I'll get
time code of where to cut things with
it. But usually there's a caut
in there somewhere that says after you
do these things whatever sounds good to
your ear. So if you need to adjust the
edit whatever because she trusts my ear,
she trusts my expertise. That's where
you can be kind of artsy. And then, oh,
by the way, once it's finished, I need
you to loop it. So, then you go through
this period of you knock it out, you
draft it, you send it off, you get
approval, or you might get a critique.
Knock on wood, usually I don't get a
critique. Usually, it is bingo, you're
good. Thank you, Swifty. I'm out. Or
speedy. Speedy is what I usually get
called. But it's it's one of those
things where it But it's not about me.
It's not about me being creative. It's
not about me trying to
do something like that. It's about you
have this skill set and you do it in a
creative manner.
>> You know, please execute this the way
I've asked you to. Doesn't mean I can't
interject something and say, "Hey, I was
listening to this. Would you mind?" Or
or I'll take it of my own accord and
I'll do the extra work. And whether it's
a video edit or a music edit or create
an extra queue when I used to do a lot
of lighting design, I you know, I'll
just create it. I can always omit it. I
can always take it out. Now I have two
files. It's it's faster for me. And then
I can say, I just mocked this up. Would
you listen to both, please? Or would you
look at both, please? I had an idea. You
don't have to use it. You if you love
it, I will high render it kind of thing.
But if you want to be heard and seen
that you can do other things, sometimes
you have to do stuff off the clock.
Sometimes you have to put that little
bit of extra effort in. But it's also
asking. If you don't ask, you'll never
receive. And I'm the worst at asking.
I'm really the worst. And I preach to
everybody, ask. If you don't ask, it's
always a no,
>> right?
>> It's always a no if if you don't ask.
But nobody wants to deal with rejection
or criticism.
>> Hey, I'm with you on that. It hurts.
I hate it. But but that's the one thing
I would love to impart is that that's
another issue in communication is you
have to deal with criticism and
rejection and then you have to separate
the wheat from the chaff. You have to be
able to go this is constructive. This is
someone being salty.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> Are they being salty for a reason or are
they just being salty to be salty? We
all have bad days.
>> Yeah. Well Well and in in what level of
personal
Like what level of personal insult am I
taking on to this? Something that I've
definitely had to learn is like my so
like being a D I I was certainly a DJ
before I was making my own art and
writing my own poetry and writing my own
like I like like a lot of hip-hop and I
do some producing and stuff like it took
me a long time to unwind how precious
everything felt. It's like, man, I spent
like I poured my hope and dreams and my
tears and my real thoughts and my
experience and my traumas and I I I
worked on this thing for you and like
isn't it amazing? And they're like, it's
not going to go in the show. See you
later. And you're like, but it's it's
everything. But it's like that is that
is the the continuous arc of doing
anything creatively or as an artist or
whatever is you got to let it go. You
can create it. It can come from all of
those places, but then once it's out
here, shared to everybody else,
>> it's not personal. It's you got to let
it go. It's
>> Do you think that that's a your NF
function like the the intuitive and the
feeler combined that it amplifies that?
Here I have given you this beautiful
bird. Smash, we're not using it. Thanks.
Have a great day. Like do you think that
that might play into it a little bit?
>> Yeah. I mean because you know a lot of
times I'm I'm looking for my own worth
in that sometimes. Um a lot of times I'm
not necessarily from other people. A lot
of times it's like I want to prove to
myself that I'm an artist and can make
these things and you know like whether I
want to say it out loud or not like the
way someone else reacts to what I hand
them is going to you know it's a
perspective right back on myself like
okay this view that I have of me and how
I interface and see the world
>> if it suddenly doesn't hit with somebody
else even if I know for a fact like
they're they don't think like me they're
not going to see it like me even if I
wanted them to it does take this like oh
gez maybe I'm just like a weirdo sees
the world in a weird way, you know, like
it it it becomes this personal um
inquiry onto who I am as a person. I'll
say not not so much anymore. You know,
it's um I'm able to I can create the
most precious thing and if someone
doesn't like it, it's like, well,
whatever, man. It's what I created. I
don't care, you know, it's it's less and
less these days, but um yeah.
>> Does it bleed over into an imposttor
syndrome feeling? A feeling not that you
actually have it, but does it does it
add or do you ever experience that or is
it just
Like does that extrapolate or become
something different?
>> 100%. I think um dude I and I think the
only way to unwind imposter syndrome is
to just keep doing the and like you
prove to yourself even accidentally. I
mean after a while like so often I you
know I've have I've had hundreds of
podcast guests. You know I've I've made
all this art. I've I've put myself out
there so many times and for so many
hundreds of hours in different ways
whether it's art or poetry or content
creation or DJing or whatever it is.
It's like
like
of course I'm going to feel like an
imposter, but after a while it's I don't
need anybody else to confirm for me what
I already do. I don't need a single
other person to call me a podcaster or
an artist or a poetry poet. I
write poetry every day, so I'm a poet.
You know what I mean? Like
>> Well, I was going to say it's funny
because I had this conversation with a
friend of mine who's a PhD. I have
several friends that are as you would if
you work a lot in and around education,
but someone we met when she started
working in the middle school level and I
worked with her off and on, you know, as
she went and got her doctorate. Now I
we're probably more friends than we are
colleagues, but whenever she calls, I'm
like, I'm on it. Like, what do you need?
What do you want? uh one of my favorite
people in the world. But we were talking
about imposttor syndrome and I was like
because I think she just had been having
a really rough week and I was like I
can't understand it because I don't have
it.
And as we talked about it and we we
talked through it and the short answer
to it because I'm long-winded is that I
get in over my head a lot of times like
I've since I was young I would get jump
into the deep end either intentionally
or unintentionally. So, I could end up
in a job, oh, I didn't realize I was
unprepared for some of it. And then that
could easily breed imposttor syndrome,
but I don't know if it's a function of
being able to see the bigger picture and
then zero in on key functions of that. I
go, it's just stuff I haven't learned
yet.
>> You got that job for a reason. You're
here. You are here for a reason. You
know, I can see a few places in in life
and in society where I would say, "Yeah,
imposter syndrome is probably valid
because either nepotism or other sorts
of immutable characteristics and you're
like, did I get hired for this or that?"
I could see how that could burrow into
your brain. But all in all, for anybody
that deals with it, as I've talked with
a lot of my friends who have it, I say
just take it on as it's stuff that you
haven't done yet or you haven't learned
yet or if you're already doing it,
you're already doing it. You don't need
external validation. Like you exactly
what you were saying. As long as you
know, okay, I've done it. Like it would
be like someone saying to you, "Oh,
well, you're not an audio engineer
because you didn't do this one thing
over here." Or you got on the job site
and you were asked to work a board
you've never worked before and you're
like, "Oh crap, this is going to be a
learning curve and it's a fast one and a
short one."
So, I would say if you can take a step
back from the situation, if you start
feeling that feeling of whatever
imposter syndrome feels like to you and
kind of go, "No, I know all of this
stuff. It's just one little piece."
Okay, it's one little piece of the
puzzle. Got it. I can I can work on one
little piece. Play to your strengths,
work on your weaknesses, hide your
faults. I say it all the time. Play to
your strengths, work on your weaknesses,
hide your faults.
Yeah, I I like that when you So, you you
had mentioned that in in one of the
articles that I read of you. Um, can you
tell me more about this hiding your
faults because I think that's actually
like a really dope I I actually really
love that because it sound I think on
the surface it sounds like what do you
mean hide your fault? You like you got
going to be dishonest or something, man.
But it's not that. I think it's it's
definitely not that. Can you elaborate
more on hiding your faults?
>> Well, I think it started with my
generation being lied to. You can't do
any and everything. like I'm not short.
I'm over 6 feet tall. There are certain
things I am not going to be able to do
that my friend who is 5 foot nothing can
do. Right? So like and that's just it's
a genetic thing. There's nothing I can
do about it. It is what it is and that's
okay. That is absolutely okay. But I
have friends of mine who come to me all
the time because they're mothers and
they own their businesses and they're
working and they're the primary bread
winner and they're burning the candle at
every end. And she's like, "We were sold
a lie." And I said, "I told you that 15
years ago, almost maybe maybe more like
12 or 13 because we've known each other
for 16." So, probably more like 12 or 13
years ago. But it was like, "No, our
generation was lied to. You can't do it
all. You can try to and you can accept
that it's not going to always work.
That's a fault. We were sold an
unrealistic set of expectations. We're
trying to live up to something that
cannot happen. That is a fault. but I'm
really good at these things over here.
If you're in a business setting, people
are not going to invest in something
that's failing.
You know, you may find an angel donor
that out of the goodness of their kind
heart is willing to step up and they
need the tax write off. Two things can
be true at once, right? They can be
generous and want the tax write off.
Nothing wrong with that. Uterior
motives, right? and they're not always
nefarious and negative, but in that
situation, you have to hide not in a
negative way of disclosing it. You don't
have to tell everybody everything.
>> It's not your if I walked on, if you
knew how sick I had been before we did
the show this year and how badly I felt
sitting there with you in the hallway
editing music, I felt like trash. I
wasn't I didn't have a fever. It wasn't
anything like that. But I did not feel
good. I'm not I have to hide that.
>> You didn't tell me about it a single
time. I didn't know about it at all.
>> I mean, I certain people knew cuz I was
like I might I almost didn't do the
show. I was I was I had been that sick
for that long because I've been
traveling and I'd been on a dance
competition convention and I was
pounding it every weekend, flying out,
flying out, flying out. And then in
between I had other gigs like an award
show that I direct and a coral
performance that I was doing and I was
pinging and just burning the candle at
every end almost and because it just
happens to be that season but I'm the
fault that I'm hiding in that situation
is the fact that I am kind of miserable.
It's it's it's like I when you got to go
you got to go kind of situation but you
can be delicate with things. I would say
it's being polite. It's being proper.
It's being congenial. It's being
cordial. It's waspy society. Hi, here's
the varnish. Here's the veneer. It's the
Vaseline on the lens. Right? You don't
need to know all the flaws and you don't
need to always see all the way behind
the curtain.
>> So, that's what I'm talking about with
faults. We all have them. We all have
like those little things, but if you're
going to play to your strength, this is
what I do really well. And you can be
honest about,
you know what I mean? I need to work on
these things. and and I recognize that I
do, but I'm actively working on them.
Please work on them.
>> Right. Right.
>> But a fault isn't necessarily being
shady. It isn't being deceptive. And I
think that's that's what I mean by it.
It's not I'm not being deceptive with
it. It is I don't need to sit there and
moan and groan. Like if I was sitting
there moaning and groaning the entire
time and being huffy and
it's not going to do anything for the
morale around me.
>> No. Well, in in what you find, I mean,
really in any work situation is the um
kind of the inevitable like complaining
trauma bonding that that starts to
happen 100 like the and Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. totally. And it's, you know, it's
it's a human thing, but I think man, so
I had this uh this guy Trevor May, he's
a he played uh in the MLB. He's he's
from the same hometown as me. He's he's
really cool. I had him on the podcast
and um we talked about this thing and I
don't know if he exactly said it or if I
had brought it up because I had heard it
but regardless we talked about it
essentially like if you're a baseball
player and you strike out like dude that
sucks, right? That sucks. Like you're
bummed technically you let your team
down, right? But like you don't you
don't need to go to the dugout and throw
a fit and complain for the next five
minutes like I let you guys down or like
that pitcher sucks or you know whatever
it is. It's like you got out next, you
know, like we got we got a game to play
here, you know, like are you really
going to go your upset mood that you're
bummed about, you got you got struck
out, you whatever, you didn't hit the
ball, you're going to go bring that vibe
and like just, you know, cloud the whole
dugout with that energy, you know what I
mean? And so that that's a great Yeah, I
think that's a good example of of like
what you're saying, hide your faults.
You know, yes, you're sick. Yes, you're
not feeling good, but you recognize,
hey, what I could do is I can kind of
keep these complaints that I'm feeling
like, you know, my stomach hurts, but I
don't need to tell everybody right now.
That sort of stuff. I think that's
actually a pretty big factor. I think
that's actually a pretty big one, man. I
like that.
>> Thanks. I mean, it's it's something I've
thought about for years, and it's just
something I used to say as almost like a
mantra
because it's you had to remind yourself
at times because we're human. We're
going to fall into that trauma bonding,
complaining, commiserating almost. It's
more commiserating than anything. But I
I do know certain people that are energy
vampires and all they ever do and they
put the negativity into it.
>> A friend of mine was sick and had to go
take have stuff taken care of and this
one person in their life kept going, "Is
it cancer? Is it this? Is it that?" And
every time they speak, I'm like, why are
you putting that? It words have meaning.
In all seriousness, energy is all around
us. We are freaking electrons. Like, you
can't sit here and say that when I'm
going to get woo woo for a second, but
you can't say that you're not going to
jinx somebody. I have literally lived my
entire life with someone in it that if
they say certain things about your
automobile, it's going to freaking be
the next thing that goes wrong.
So, we shut it down. You know, it's
probably,
>> yes, we're all on the same page. Don't
say it. Keep it to yourself. Like, I got
it
>> now. It's become a game all these years
later. But it's just it's really funny
when you go, "No, you literally
>> Yeah.
>> You can kind of create the world around
you
>> and from that perspective." And if I
came in huffy or with a bad attitude or
miserable, but nothing will bring a
group together more than the one person
that everybody hates. Mhm.
>> It's true. I mean, I I have so many
stories like we all didn't like this one
person or they or this person's
attitude. Let me rephrase that. Just the
way this person interacted with
everybody or their attitude and it's
like and all of these groups of people
or all these individuals that wouldn't
normally communicate could all just look
at each other and go,
>> "Yeah, I that guy. Yeah, that guy
does suck."
>> And and so it builds camaraderie.
Unfortunately, the other person doesn't
get to be a part of that, but or or a
situation. It may not even be a person.
It may be a situation like this is the
worst job and you're all miserable and
you're all just going
>> but you still have to do it. You have to
get through it. You have to
>> Man, it is one of the more complicated
things though. You know, this is
something I still to this day, you know,
I I love all these psychology books and
I like Tony Robbins and I like to do my
meditation stuff and I still get caught
up in like just a couple months ago just
bitching about somebody mutually on on
the job site on on the headset, you
know, it's like it's it's a difficult
thing, but you got Man, I love that you
said jinx. You use the word jinx.
>> I like that. I I I want to use the word
spells. A lot of times we are
>> we
>> all of us whether you're you're on the
one saying this or you're the one
receiving these things in group cohesion
start to look at the way things people
say think of them as spells whether
they're good spells or or or negative
spells but like suddenly we all kind of
shift our vibe and we all kind of you
know it's like like the the lead of a
band is going to kind of bring us all to
a different you know tempo and a BPM and
a rhythm and a key and sometimes the
>> you know if if a intentional leader
doesn't take the role of the leader. A
lot of times the bully or the loudest
person becomes the lead and that could
affect everyone's mood, you know, like
one person starts complaining about how
they struck out of the dugout and
everybody's like, "Yeah, this game
sucks." And like, yeah, suddenly you're
like manifest destiny, you know? You're
you're creating more of this occurrence.
Like you said, your car breaks down
because you keep talking about how your
car always breaks down. We got to be
aware of our spells that we use, you
know? Well, and I think for me, I've
always been I would never say an
optimist. I'm I'm too realistic for
that, but I'm a potentialist. I see the
potential in people. I see the potential
in projects,
but that then bleeds over into a lot of
disappointments because nothing's ever
going to rarely, I won't say nothing
ever. It very rarely gets where you want
it to be because whatever you've created
up here then has to either you have to
physically make it happen or you have to
explain it to somebody else. And there
we go with communication again. If I
don't explain to you properly how I want
something done, you're going to get
someone's interpretation no matter what
of what you did. So I have to figure out
every single wicket. Which is why I
think a to some people I'm a control
freak. But I will give you but that's
why we have tear sheets. That's why we
have a book for shows like whether
you're doing a musical or you're doing
certain types of shows. You have a book
or a Bible that you go through and it
has images. It has reference footage if
it's digital if it's uh you know the
text needs to change if whatever it is
you can zero in to every fine. I don't
think anybody understands
how I can walk into a room of 90 to 100
young women that are dancing in this one
group and I can notice you're not
wearing the light the right false
eyelashes and I'm across the room from
you. You need to fix the nape of your
neck, your hair looks bad, the this is a
problem that and it's like God's picking
on me. No, if I'm noticing I'm not doing
this for the average person that's not
going to notice it. I'm doing it for the
me that's in the crowd. Mhm.
>> Because I do it on shows all the time. I
was like, "Oh, that wasn't supposed to
happen." But I've changed my mindset.
Like I've really rewired part of my
brain to go, "Oh no, I you know, instead
of going, "Oh, well that was da da da."
I'm now like, "Oh, I hope they're okay.
>> Oh, I hope they can get back on track.
Oh, like like my mindset is in a
completely new space."
Gosh, I don't know. at least I would say
eight years, seven, eight years ago, it
really started my mindset started
changing on a lot of things
>> and in I I want people to succeed. I
genuinely do. I may not like you. I may
not like the way you conduct yourself,
the way you comport yourself, the way
you treat other people, the way you do
business or just other things. I want
you to succeed over there.
Like just don't be in my sphere, please.
But I I do want you to succeed. I do
want good things to befall upon you
because we all have something going on
in our lives.
>> Yeah.
>> And and if we can take that beat and
realize we all have something going on
or someone around us does that we're
having to deal with,
>> you can start to go, okay, it it takes
nothing to hold the door open for
someone. What? You're going to lose 30
seconds to a minute of your day? Like
the person's hobbling towards the door.
Just hold it. Just come on. Yeah. Yeah.
>> I don't know. It's maybe it's how I was
reared, but but my mindset has really
changed about a lot of things and it's
>> I don't know.
>> Yeah. No, I mean I I think that's really
cool though because when we can notice
that we have sway on things with our
environment like holding the door open
for someone is is a good example. A lot
of times it's kind of a movement of not
choosing selfishness, right? Because
it's like without really thinking about
it, you're you're you're going into the
door. You know, you're walking in,
you're not really thinking about other
people. You've got your whatever
whatever's inside that building, that's
what you're thinking about. But for a
second, if you could I open the door,
I'm inside the building. Glance over
real quick, see that someone's on their
way. Suddenly, you can go from having
zero impact on someone's day or maybe
even like you just they felt felt it was
rude that you didn't even look over and
let the door shut. But you could
suddenly tell someone good morning. Say,
hey, I got you. Yeah, you're in there.
Like someone might have been in their
own head. they're nervous about whatever
they're walking into that building for.
And you could, you know, uh, like allow
that energy to dissipate a little bit by
just saying, "Oh, I got you. Come on in.
Yeah, welcome. Good morning. How are
you?" Like, whatever. You know, like I
think that we all have a lot more power.
We take for granted the amount of power
that we have um to create good vibes. I
know that's a sentence, right? But like
you hold the door open for somebody, you
say good morning, whatever, and now
there's a little smile on your face.
There's a smile on their face. Whatever
they're doing after this has nothing to
do with you, but you just caused a
smile. It could have rippling effects
downstream. It could have domino effects
of them now being more warm and inviting
to whatever they're walking into. You
know,
>> just helping someone pick something up.
You might they might have arthritis.
They may have an issue that doesn't even
it's internal. You don't see it. They
may have vertigo. Who knows, you know?
they may have an issue, but just helping
someone pick something up and hand it to
them kind of thing, you know? It's those
are definitely
just little things like that. There are
times where you don't make eye contact.
There are times where you don't smile at
people. There are times when it could be
a safety problem.
>> Sure.
>> Like a hazard or a concern and you need
you need to be careful about that. So, I
I want to acknowledge especially with
women there there are a lot of times
where you don't smile at a male. You
don't because he will misinterpret
something. You know, you don't there
there are times where you need to
protect yourself. So, I'm not ever
saying step out of if your gut feels
like you need to be protected.
>> Yeah.
>> Don't do it. But in general general
day-to-day life, it it's not going to
hurt you to to just
hashtag be kind. But but but in all
seriousness, kindness and nice kindness
is not niceness. Mhm.
>> Kind, nice, and good are three different
words. They mean three different things.
Kind of back to our earlier
conversation. Kindness and goodness have
one word in common, and that's
benevolence. And you've done something.
You've stepped outside of yourself and
done something even without expectation.
I opened a door for somebody, didn't
expect anything out of it, and all of a
sudden you got a great thank you or you
ended up in a conversation and or
whatever. Or you just made somebody's
day better or easier.
>> Fantastic. But also, your emergency is
not my emergency. So, that's the other
thing because I've worked sales long
enough. Do not come in
>> demanding things of me. Like, take a
beat. Be polite. There's so many people
that treat the service industry as if,
well, you're the service industry. I'm
like I I'm really thinking about in
contracts if hiring people you need to
have a year's worth of service industry
work. I really think it would be
important. It can be retail, it can be,
you know, working at a restaurant,
barback, you know, whatever. But where
in a full year, it doesn't have to be
consecutive. Like you could do it every
summer during college, but there are a
lot of places where if you have never
worked in the service industry on any
level, phone calls, internet, you name
it, you do not know how to interact with
people
>> and how to how to lock it up and try to
diffuse the situation or how to there's
this pervasive attitude I keep seeing
because there are a couple people that
are online that like, I'll meet you
where you met me. And I'm like, there's
a time and a place for that.
>> And and that's a very juvenile way of
looking at it. I'm not saying don't do
it. I'm saying try to deescalate first
and then if you need to be like, "No,
but seriously, we're going to lock this
down right now."
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> But but try to deescalate it.
>> Yeah. I mean, I I love your emergency is
not my emergency. I think that's a
really good one. I I think that often we
are being invited to be like, "Hey, you
know, you're just naturally level two,
but like be at level eight right now
because that's where I'm at." And a lot
of times the answer is like, you know,
I'll go up to three or four, but like
we're we're good here. Well, we don't
need to yell at each other just because
you feel like yelling. You know, your
emergency is not my emergency. I think
it's a good one.
>> Well, but then the flip side of that is
if we're on a work site, your emergency
better be my emergency.
>> Fair enough. Yeah,
>> because you and I both know what what I
don't think people the mystery one of
the mystics behind a live show, right? A
lot of times it's if it's a concert,
they're usually rolling in at O dark in
the morning, setting up the rigging for
the lighting and the sound, setting up
the stage, setting up the tech booth,
and then first thing in the morning when
normal people would wake up is when
people the rest of the crew starts to
roll in to set up their equipment. And
then midday performers start to come in
to do sound check, to do floor checks,
with dance rehearsal, to do all the
different things. And if it's a one
night event, it's all torn down by 2
a.m. Like you have to tear everything
you just watched down. So nobody I don't
think people really understand the
compressed time. I mean that's an
extreme one but even if you're doing any
sort of touring or any sort of show you
are flying in and you max will have 48
hours for a lot of things max.
So let's let's talk about the the dance
convention I work with. Venues are
astronomically expensive a lot of times.
So, if I've paid I'm going to pick just
an average number of $20,000
for a 3-day weekend. I'm coming in
midday Friday and I'm leaving uh by 900
p.m. Sunday.
20 grand is just the venue. So, that's
my lobby. That's my dressing room.
Possibly a breakout room if we're lucky
and a green room, you know, that sort of
thing. And the stage
that that's what you're getting. That's
not the money you're paying for the
crew. That's going to work your event
each day, which is going to be an hourly
rate, which if you go over on time,
could become time and a half.
>> You could end up with fees and dues
there. You can't always
>> like that's I'm the time clock on a lot
of things. So, I'm the one that's like,
"We're about to hit over. Just speed it
up." You know what I mean? So, your
emergency needs to be my emergency in
that situation. like we need we you
don't understand this is going to cost
us a quarter of what we've spent for
this entire event. We're going to have
to pay a quarter more. But you don't
care because you don't understand that
section of the umbrella.
>> Yeah.
>> That's not that's not paying for talent.
That's not paying for your staff and
your talent and that's not paying for
the food. That's not paying. So just
think 20 grand is your starting base
price. And if I flew anybody in and
there's lodging and all of that for
people.
>> Yeah.
>> So now you're dealing with this thing
that one minute if you show up one
minute late that's hundreds of dollars
that you have wasted.
>> Y
>> So when somebody comes in, oh it's just
a minute. It is not just a minute. So I
get very frustrated when people don't
open venues on time or they're just
driving up. We are in at 7:30. That
means you as anybody working the venue
needs to be there 15 minutes early. That
door needs to be I understand keeping it
locked, but at 8 a.m. or 7:30 a.m. or
whatever it is, you that door needs to
be you need to be opening it for me
unless some emergency has happened
because I get it. You're just doing your
clockin job because you work for the
venue. But I've done that job before and
I understand
there's money being wasted and it's not
fair for you to waste our money and our
time. That's right there is time is
money and your emergency needs to be my
emergency.
>> Yeah.
>> But when you're running into a store
going, "My daughter forgot her tights
and d and I need you to pull all this
stuff and look on my account and I don't
know what it is and I'm on my phone and
and it's like can you hurry up?"
>> Yeah. Yeah. That's Yeah.
>> Two different scenarios, two different
situations. I will help you as quickly
as I can help you. But just because you
came in like a whirling dervish, there's
a line.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> And there only two of us here. We we
will try to help you really quickly, but
>> you know, and someone in line may allow
you to get in front, cut in front of
them. Somebody may do the generous thing
like we were talking about before and
let you because they see that you're
having a thing.
>> Yeah.
>> I don't know.
>> Anyway, there's some examples.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Well, I I mean, but I think
something that does happen in that
environment, it's you know, I think
entitlement sometimes does leak over
like you said, people who haven't
>> people who haven't worked the service
industry. I just think that per that's a
good example of like going to a store
and going, "Hey, my daughter needs
tights and it's the thing blah blah
blah." And like they it's okay for them
to be like it's reasonable that they're
stressed out. They probably got a lot
going on, like whatever. But walking
into a place and saying,
>> "You're in customer service. serve me
right now to my highest, you know, like
that's just a different situation.
That's that's um um yeah, I mean I I I
think that there is yeah, your emergency
can be my emergency. There still needs
to be respect. There's there's still not
an ownership that you have over someone
just because they work, you know, a
minimum wage job at some store or
something like you don't you don't get
to walk in and tell them what to do. You
don't have that entitlement over them.
>> Well, would you please
would you please
>> please and thank you. I mean, I swear.
And I was reared. It was beaten into me
verbally as a child, you know, manners,
manners, manners, manners, manners. But
I find that because so few people were
reared with that kind of background
>> that and of no fault of their own,
right?
That
>> we don't do it as much in society. And
so it goes way farther.
>> I mean, I don't realize how much I
please and thank you on a set. I really
don't. But I think it's like every, you
know, 10 sentences it's a please or a
thank you and and it's it's ingrained.
It's wrote, but I mean it
>> because I'm not going to say it if I
don't mean it.
>> Like you So that that's kind of it's
like don't judge me by who I'm around.
Judge me about who I kicked out of my
life. Go see you start asking yourself
why they're not there anymore. Because
sometimes you're stuck in situations
where you're around people and they're
not your inner circle. They're attached
to someone that's in your inner circle.
But in work, it's very much like that.
No, I'm I'm here. I'm doing my job. I'm
doing my thing. But there's no reason
for me to not be cordial and congenial
until you really mess something up. And
I have to go, no, we need to we need to
have a conversation and it needs to be
the right time and place. And this is
not it, but we do not make me have to
pull you aside right now because I don't
have time for this.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Because I've had that
happen like like where I've watched it
and I've gone, "Oh no, this is going to
go badly and like and you're sitting
there on the sidelines going tamp it
down, tamp it down, tamp it down. Oh,
this is going to escalate. Okay, I'm
just going to sit over here on the
sideline with my popcorn.
>> This is going
>> Yeah, we see where this is going kind of
thing. So, but I think another part of
communication is
>> learning to be cordial and cenial.
>> A please and thank you. I have seen so
this is why I say nice isn't kind isn't
good. Good isn't nice. Nice just means
harmless. It means you don't want to
rock the boat or it's a facade you adopt
to make yourself look a certain way.
>> Virtue signal. Yeah.
>> That or you know you're really
I was going to use a specific uh
pop star as as my example of nice versus
everything else, but I I'll refrain from
that. People can guess on who I'm
talking or thinking about, but there
have been people in my life where they
present a certain societal image, but
because I was in the inner circle, I
know the exact opposite. So, I sit there
and go, if you're going to speak this
way of other people,
>> when is it going to turn around and bite
me?
>> I very well I and it did.
>> The second you leave the room, that's
when
>> Well, not always. like sometime well
okay maybe it it depends on the
situation but that's why I've seen some
really jerky people do the kindest deeds
some of the people that would just rip
you a new one that had no manners and
I've just seen them do some of the
kindest things quietly
just very quietly and I just happened to
I just happened to be there and it
really those moments have stuck with me
where it's like Okay, that's the that's
kindness. That's that's benevolence.
Like you did something. You took time
out of your day. You didn't have to. You
look like you were about to go in on
somebody and then you realized there's
something else at play here and you
stopped yourself
>> and you worked with the person. None of
the rest of us were going to get that
treatment. You know what I mean? But I
was like, "Oh." And I think observation
is a form of communication
>> because if you don't if you're not
paying attention, if you're not aware of
what's around you, if you're just kind
of surfacily taking it in and letting it
wash over you, you're not really
observing what's around you, there's so
much you can learn by non-verbal cues.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> And how people interact with each other.
That's why, you know, it's
>> it's just difficult. You know what I
mean? So I
>> to be articulate is one thing. You have
some people really have to work at it. I
learned I'm not great acting on a stage.
I I can perform till the cows come home,
but if acting was never my strong suit.
>> Give me a microphone, throw me behind a
lectern or throw me up on the stage with
some crib notes about what I need to
talk about or like a bullet point
outline. Boom. I can vamp. I I I can
make it work.
>> It just for whatever reason, because
it's me, I'm not having to pretend to be
another character. If I mess something
up, I can crack my own joke about it. I
have control in that situation. So,
maybe it's a control freak issue. Maybe
I am a control freak.
>> Um, but I I can sit there and
communicate and then you can if there's
a crowd, I can vibe off of that. I know,
oh, this isn't working. This is working.
I think that's why I've become the voice
of God for the dance competition stuff
because it's like I'll flub and people
will come up to me afterwards and I'll
be having a bad day and I'll get razed
like you know that's that's you you
called it la soul fads and it's laser
feed you know what I mean but I'm just I
I've gone into teleprompter mode and I'm
just reading and I'm tired and I'm on
number 200 and you know you're not
paying attention and so someone comes
and razes you about it.
You're just like, you can take that and
be defeated with it.
>> All the words I said correctly, you're
mad about that one,
>> but they're but someone's engaging with
you, they they're they're correcting
you, but they're also trying to have fun
with you as well. And so, if you can
take it in the spirit in which it is
meant, because when you're tired, you're
going to get moody about whatever. It's
It's happened before where I'm like,
really, that's what we're going to do
now.
But it doesn't help backstage. I'm
dealing with children, like little
children all the way up to teenagers. I
have parents sometimes. I have studio
owners. I have um teachers.
>> I set the tone for backstage.
I do like, you know, I'm not in the back
booth. When I'm in the back booth, I'm
not setting the tone for anything but
the booth. You know what I mean? But I'm
an omnipresent person. That is a world
that I'm in charge of. And people have
entrusted their children around me.
>> And so they need to be safe and they
need to be okay, you know, and so it's
very much I don't know. I work really
well with children. I I I just I always
have. I I never forgot what it was. Most
people are like, "Oh, I didn't think you
would work well with children. I didn't
think you liked them." I was like, "I
don't like things on mass." You know
what I mean? But I do like children.
Like they're learning. And if you can
set a good example, why not do it? Why
not take that opportunity? I don't have
to indoctrinate you. There's no reason
for you to know anything about my life.
But if I comport myself in a very
specific way, keep a very specific
demeanor, and I'm consistent. That's
what children need.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Consistency. People, humans in general,
need consistency. It can boil over into
monotony very quickly, but we all need
consistency on some level
>> and children especially. So, if you can
be that consistent figure, like they're
nervous to come talk to you because you
have the clear calm on and you have the
microphone in front of your mouth and
you're sitting there and you you're
you're tall and you're big and all that
sort of stuff
>> and you're serious. So, and I have major
RBF like like it it gets very stern,
very Germanic Nordic serious lock in. So
that people can be very nervous to come
talk to you. But when a teacher says,
"No, go talk to him." Or I get out of
that headsp space and I'm checking
students in, I'll just sit on the floor.
>> You know what I mean? Or I'll kneel
down. Come down to someone's level. And
I don't mean lower yourself. I mean you
physically
>> are not opposing. You're not this
ominous figure.
>> Making approachable. Yeah.
>> 100%. And then you can brighten up. And
then you can bring on the real smile.
I'd had a really rough show.
this season like there was one really
really rough one and I turned around and
like things were just not going
correctly and I was like we have to
start in 10 minutes we're going to go
over time things were not going right
and I I was so frustrated I couldn't
figure out what to do
and the you know the owner wasn't there
for the city like it was it was there
was a lot on my shoulders for the city
and I kind of went no I can't I can do
something I can check children in I can
check the students in for the
performance. I can sit there and ignore
everything else that's bothering me and
I can park my backside on the stage and
just start making sure and asking them
how they pronounce their name so I can
get it correctly and I can do all the
things. It changed my mood. It took a
few minutes, but I mean just because
there's they didn't do anything wrong.
There's no reason for me to have a tude.
There's no reason for me to act a
certain kind of way. I'm dealing with
all of this stress and I'm very angry at
a couple of things in the situation.
It's okay.
>> Yeah,
>> we're gonna make it okay. Do not that
energy does not need to be backstage.
So, I have to take that down.
>> Yeah.
>> I mean, I was flat out told by an a
company owner one time, it's like, it
doesn't help me when you get in this
headsp space.
>> It doesn't help me at all. when you when
you get into that burn it down headsp
space, it's not helping me at all. I
need you to go take a beat. Like, we
need we need to figure it out. And we
have I have cues with people and they
have cues with me when it's like a day
where they're not vibing. It's like one
of my colleagues says, "I'm having a
really raw day. This has been a a week.
Done. Got it. I know exactly where you
are." That phrase would mean something
for somebody else, but I know where you
are. Got it. I'm not feeling great and
I've told you I'm not feeling great. I
have to I have to get out of my head
space and I have to step up for you.
That person did it for me. You know
where it's like I don't like seeing you
this way and so they would run
interference for me.
>> Yeah.
>> And it's and it's
>> that's being a colleague. That's
communication. That's communication. I
mean just
>> I was going to say that's another
perfect example of communication. I love
that we've ended up just like
emphasizing communication to the nth
degree in this podcast. That's really
good. I think that's like super
valuable.
>> I mean, I didn't mean to. It's just it's
it's kind of I never would have thought
that that would have been as important
or to our dialogue right now,
especially.
>> No, I mean, I I think it is though
because I I mean, so we we're getting up
here in time and I do kind of want to
round the corner here. Um, but something
that I something that I wanted to cover
is uh I mean, it's perfect for where
we're at right here. It's like, you
know, you're talking about you're this
you're this role for in this example.
You know, there's a lot of young people
around and they're able to, you know,
I'm sure you're intimidating to them in
in multiple ways. It's intimidating
situation for them in general. You know,
they're nervous.
>> Yeah. Yeah. All these factors, but
you're able to you have a leadership
position and you're able to find ways
that you can uh, you know, most
comfortably and most efficiently step
into that leadership position. So, you
clearly have learned, you know, outside
of you, you have these natural abilities
of of things that we've already
discussed um in different things that
you noticed about yourself as a child,
but you've clearly had mentors along the
way. You've had teachers along the way,
you've had um you know, so so I guess
for me, I want to leave that really
broad for you to kind of talk about your
mentors and like what you've learned
from them, how they've changed you, and
this is even when you were younger,
maybe it was last year you had a mentor.
Um I I would love to just kind of like o
open that gate for you Curtis of just
mentors, people you have learned from um
your teachers along the way. What are
some traits that they have? What have
you learned from them and like how does
it shape who you are now and how you
teach and mentor?
>> Okay, this is going to be long-winded
and it's going to be splatter guy.
>> No. Yeah, please do all day. Go ahead.
>> So So I'll try to keep it into things
that you can use as digestible sound
bites. um starting I just had a really
good foundation growing up because I was
really early with a lot of things. My
mother was like, "We're getting you out
of the house." Like like we're going to
put you in museum school. We're going to
put you in music school. You're going to
go to prek. You're going to go to
preschool and prek. Like I I was in
school at a very as soon as you know
you're potty trained, you could go kind
of thing. I was in some form of
schooling.
Take that. I my kindergarten class was
highly musical.
She had a piano in her classroom. She
could play the guitar. She played the
piano. She could sing. And not only was
it a musical classroom because there
were two kindergartens in the private
where I went to private school. I ended
up I just by the fortune of God ended up
in hers. I I will always go back to some
of those formative years because we
would do these books where I don't know
what your kindergarten or elementary
school situation was like, but when I
was in school, they'd have these books
that were about probably that big and
they'd have a letter on it, capital A,
lowercase A, capital B, lowercase B. So
that would be the unit you were
learning. And for one whole week, you
would go through each page of it and you
would do basically like units within the
book. And it was structured like Ted and
Fred sat and had an apple. And you know,
you had your reading assignments, you
had your writing assignments to work on
your dexterity and all that. But in her
classroom, she would also take with each
letter unit construction paper pieces
that we would glue together to create
George the gray gorilla wearing green
glasses playing a guitar.
And so there would be a narrative
associated with the letter, with the
character, with the this, with the that.
And maybe it was every two weeks that we
would switch it the book out. I don't
I was five, but but it would be like
Sammy the stinky skunk or smelly skunk
and she would bring her husband's
cologne in and put it on this little
construction paper skunk and she'd hang
it on this lanyard around her room. We
would do like little performances in the
classroom. It was a very structured
classroom, but there was room, you know.
We would we would get up out of the
desks and we would sit down and she'd
play at the piano or she'd play the
guitar. You know, you have all the
stickers on your homework. You know, if
you got above a 95, you got the scratch
and sniff sticker. You know, if you got
an A, you got the, you know, whatever
metallic sticker.
After that, it took a long time before I
had
teachers where I really vibed. I'm not
gonna say anything negatively about them
because different era, different time
where you learn and how you learn. You
know, I've been in the educator adjacent
position and mentorship position. It's
not as easy as people think it is.
>> You know, and and there's a lot of
management that goes on. So, as a
student, the the educator or the teacher
that is more of a disciplinarian is
going to be the jerk every time. If that
if that makes any sort of sense, you're
always just going to be like, I don't
have the freedom to do what I want to
do. You shouldn't at a certain level.
But moving to the next one, I ended up
transferring schools. I was in public
school. My fifth grade teacher, Tina
Dorsy, was amazing. She, once again,
creative projects in the classroom. Like
I remember doing this shadow box because
we would have to do these books and it
was like you could do one of five or six
different things. You're going to have
to read five or six different books and
each one you'd pick, you know, am I
going to do a book report? Am I going to
do a shadow box? Am I going to do a
presentation? Am I going to do a this or
that?
>> And once you'd used one of those up, you
couldn't use it for the next project. So
the first book I did was 20,000 Leagues
Under the Sea. And I did a shoe box for
it and created a nautilus and a squid
with dowel rods on the back that you
could they could battle each other
within it. And I had like all these like
art supplies that I'd kept for a while
with mesh. So when there was a hole in
the top so light could come in and a
hole in the side and you could look at
it from different angles. And because it
was mesh it would give you as close of
an equivalency. Like nowadays you'd go
buy LED lights and put it on a little
timer switch. It would be really fancy.
But for 1992, like I think it was a
skylight that you Yeah,
>> exactly. But she put it we did in that
classroom we did uh
picture book projects. We had someone
come into the classroom who was an
author and created picture books and
explained to us that would document
things. And so we had a presentation and
part of the assignment was we would go
take all of these pictures and then she
would have them pressed into a book. I
don't know where my book is but but
hardback like and you know at that point
in time it wasn't like you could just go
to Shutterfly like you actually had to
go to a printing
>> company to print it. So the amount of
work that this one teacher Tina Dorsy
put into her classroom
like just for the students and I like
and maybe some of the other classes did
the same thing as well and it was
curriculum and I didn't realize it. It
was the demeanor and the vibe and the
the ability to let you kind of run and
then snatch you back and rein you back
in
>> and be creative. So she allowed me to go
off on tangents. Clearly I'm good at
that. But she she allowed me to go off
on them and they would snatch me back
and go, "Okay, and now we're shutting it
down." But she didn't just truncate it
like some teachers would because she
knew that at some point
>> I was going to get somewhere. There was
going to there was there was a there was
an angle. What's the angle? And can we
get to it? We're not going to get to it
anytime soon. Okay. Have a nice day.
>> Right. Right. Right. But I would say
like anybody that knows me jumping to
high school would say Tim Hood, media
technology and productions teacher. I
had a fight with the counselors to get
into the class. I wanted to be in tech
theater so badly. We were on something
called accelerated block scheduling.
>> For anybody that doesn't know
accelerated block, it's you have four
quarters in the school year. So four
quarters. Each quarter is the equivalent
to a semester. So you effectively in one
semester
can get rid of in nine weeks you would
get rid of health, speech, a computer
class, anything like that. In 18 weeks,
so the first semester it's a year's
worth of work. So it's like you're
running through it. No one I don't think
does it anymore. They all do some weird
version of uh AB block scheduling that I
hate, but you had like an hour and 20
minutes for each class. So they wouldn't
put me in tech theater, but it was run
by the same teacher and I didn't realize
that. So I'm sitting in the counselor's
office going, "What what can I take? I'm
not going to take speech. I'm I found
out I could clap out of it. I'm not
going to take it. I'll do it my senior
year and clap out of it." She's like,
"No, but you need I'm I'm doing it my
way. This is what we're doing." So she
was telling me about the computer
classes and and blah blah blah. And like
the second or third class mentioned was
media technology.
And she immediately glossed over it and
kept going forward. And I went, "Wait,
wait, you said media. What's this media
class?" And she's like, "Oh, they just
play with cameras in there." I was like,
"That's the one."
>> Yeah.
>> We're playing with cameras. We're doing
what?
>> Sign me up.
>> Exactly. And she was like, "You don't
want to be in there with those kids." I
think the counselors were intentionally
trying to It had just become accredited
as a class and I think they were trying
to kill the class
>> probably. Yeah. Probably didn't think it
was going anywhere. Not a big deal.
Yeah.
>> Exactly. It's it's now the program the
gold star seal program. It's the magnet
program for the Fort Worth ISD.
>> Like you get bust into that program to
they've literally taken over the entire
half of the hallway that we used to be
on. Like it's just insane how that
department has grown.
>> That's cool.
>> But we also did it was the actual the
true tech theater class because in tech
theater they just painted and built
sets. That's where I learned lighting
design. That's why I learned how to run
live audio. That's where I learned audio
editing, video editing, uh, studio
camera work, uh, switchers, like
everything. It was such a hodgepodge
course. And he's the teacher, Tim Hood,
is the one that ripped me a new one
backstage.
I was running microphones for the
musical, and we'd had a costume issue.
We'd gone through all the rehearsals.
Nothing was a problem. It was a quick
change. We're doing the musical Damn
Yankees. Lola exits stage right. I'm
stage right have to rip the mic off of
her and they're the old lavalier mics.
So for anybody that doesn't know the law
of mics, those are the ones that you see
clipped on everybody for talk shows, but
it was one with a huge bell pack and had
the antenna that had to be hanging out
of the cord because if it was tucked in,
it wasn't going to get the signal. We're
talking old school, old school. And
you're having to fish this line up and
it was it was a thing. So, she had her
quick change, met me stage left, and I
had to
clip the the belt pack on her trunks,
but clip it inside out, but make sure
the wire was out. And then she had to
fish the line up into it's a it was a
halter top with a ruffle kind of bust
section. And then around the lower part
of it, it had all these ruffles. Well,
after all of the rehearsals, the seams
were coming undone at the bottom hymn
>> and all those cords got tangled. So,
she's late for her entrance on stage.
It's the big act one ender, whatever
Lola wants. She has her song in dance
routine. She's late. The devil's
vamping. Like, we're we're going like
crazy. And she just rips it off and
chucks it at me. And there are three of
us there. And none of us could stop Lola
from going on stage. And I'm having a
meltdown.
>> Yeah.
>> Going, oh no, you had one job and you
couldn't even do that, right?
>> You you one job.
>> So the audio engineer comes back, the
student one comes back and tries to to
give me the business and then all the
girl my the gaggle of gals around me
just ripped him a new one. He went back
and my teacher came in and I mean it
it's a scene from the show center stage
backstage poking his finger in my
sternum barking at me. And of course by
this I'm like 5'11 at this point and
he's 5 foot something. So he's just
looking up at me just just you don't
ever d the kind of thing that a parent
in today's day and age would flip. You
know what I mean? It's abusive. It's
this. It's that no, it wasn't. It was
the best thing that ever happened to me.
Why? Because guess what's going on some
of the time on those clearcoms when
we're on set as adults.
>> I got it at 14 years of age. 14 and a
half almost to the day. And I'm
literally sitting there. I melted down.
Like not in front of him, but I went
backstage, had my little cry moment,
picked myself back up, never have made
that mistake again. And there are a lot
of other mistakes I have never made
again. It's a life-defining moment as
Dr. Phil would say. And I say that to
say
>> it's not always abusive. It's not always
this. There are times when it is. But
that situation wasn't. But if somebody
were to look at it from the outside or
they got too much in their feelings,
>> but I didn't. I had one job and I didn't
do it
>> right.
>> Trust me. Once again, never had that
problem. But along the way he we morphed
from teacher student to colleague mentor
after Id graduated and ultimately became
friends before he passed away. So and I
think part of that
>> was because a good friend of mine who
was also in the program he was the audio
engineer and I was the lighting guy.
That's how we were kind of known and we
both edited music and all the things. P
was shot my senior year. So the week
before homecoming he died and they had a
very close relationship. So I think you
know then you have to take care of
everybody around you like that really
clouds things but it changes your
relationship and a lot is put on your
shoulders and you're able if since I was
able to communicate well and
>> do that he always wanted me to go into
education and it was just not my vibe
like I just don't like the bureaucracy
of it. It's kind of I like learning. I
like mentoring. I like educating. I like
all that stuff,
>> but man, I don't like the rules and the
structure kind of thing.
>> So, that gives you like a high school
perspective. Collegiately, I've had a
couple in various programs and classes.
My radio, television, film
uh professor. There's one in particular,
Dr. Melinda Leven.
Love her to bits. We haven't we try to
keep in contact, but you know, it's
everybody's so busy. life gets in the
way of getting ahead. But she's the one
that in her documentary making class,
she's the one I was talking about
earlier when I'd said gave
Oh, it's something about editing that we
were talking about earlier. Anyway, but
one of the best pieces of advice I ever
got came from her. Do you really need
it?
As an editor, do you really need it?
You're making all these excuses why you
want it. Do you need it? It's helped me
in my personal life. When you can start
going, "Wait a second. It's not It's not
just about work. Do I really need that
or do I just want it?" It's okay, but
just be open with yourself.
>> But she's the reason I have the um
silver remy award for the documentary
short that I produced because I produced
it in her class. and she said with a
little re-edit I think this would be a
cute a good little piece not cute but a
good little piece to submit to festivals
and so I screened at several festivals
not a ton I you know I know so much more
now that I did then I did like 22 I
would I would do things a little
differently but I have an award and it
was because she pushed me for it I
wouldn't have thought to do it myself
>> and we she and I stayed in contact for
years afterwards. Like I would drive up
to and we'd go have lunch and it was
more of a congenial colleague thing. You
know, we'd have differing opinions on
things, but because it's not a teacher
student or an educator student
relationship, we could have those
conversations. I don't believe that as
an educator, you should know that much
about me.
My personal life, yeah, if you're
married, they're going to find out. If
you have children, they're going to find
out. You don't really need to know much
more than that. my religious background.
You don't really need to know. You don't
need to know my political viewpoints.
You don't need any of that information.
Uh because it bleeds over into
indoctrination too quickly.
>> And people are right that that is an
issue because I'll see students come
into the classroom and in certain
classes that they have, there will be
teachers that are pushing one thing or
the other. And I'm like, this needs to
be a neutral space. This needs to be a
come as you are and a neutral space. and
I need to give you empirical information
or different viewpoints and they can be
countered to what I believe.
>> Here's the here's the flip side of
something and that's what some of the
best educators have ever done for me and
that's going to bring me I'll give you
one more example when it comes to just
education specifically and that is my
sixth no seventh grade reading teacher.
>> Her classroom was so freaking creative.
She was one of those teachers I was
talking about earlier. She's not a
teacher. She is a true educator and I
think she was done kind of dirty by the
school system, but she her I don't
remember her first name, but Randolph,
Mrs. Randolph, shout it out. Uh her
daughter was my grade level. And
in her classroom, she would take what
you had to do as an assignment and we
wouldn't necessarily do it in the book.
She wanted us to be very socially
conscious. So, she would have us go out
and find articles and do whatever
diagramming or do whatever the lesson
plan was on the article. I need a one
page. I need it need to be this long. I
need it to be about this. This needs to
be about the arts. This and every week
we had to do some sort of small article
like just like a like a little column
blurb because at that point we weren't
the internet was nothing like it is now.
you had to literally type httpwww
whatever to get anywhere. There is no
Google, there is no Yahoo, you know,
it's not like it is today. So, you
physically had to read the newspaper. So
in in saying all of this uh then we
would she would extrapolate that and
turn it into
assignments where she would do talk
shows and she'd be the host of the talk
show and you would have to act out as a
skit in her classroom
>> as the panel and the audience and the
audience could ask questions. She'd
bring in the PA system from the library.
She'd completely rearrange her
classroom. We do mock trials in there.
Same concept. She's the judge. And each
class, you know, you at some point had
you were in the jury pit and some point
you were prosecutor or defense or you
were on the stand depending on what pods
you were in. You would come in for those
units and the classroom would be
completely rearranged. She think about
all the time it would take someone to
just re Yeah.
>> One person rearranging all of her desks
>> and doing all of this. I I think about
it now and think about what she put into
that classroom. How much extra time she
gave to us and the gift of being able to
look at
what's around you in your everyday life
in a different way
>> but still use the systems structure
>> the framework of it
>> to explore that. So, she's still doing
what she's supposed to be doing. And
then we would cram for test taking
season. It was like, "Oh, we got to do
standardized test. We got to cram for
that." But, you know, it I mean, well,
she was the one that figured out where
my problem was with standardized test
taking.
>> She she pulled me aside one day and she
said, "Will you explain to me why you
answered why you changed these
questions?" I was like, "Well, when you
read the question this way, this is the
answer that you get." But then I did
what you said and you know you go back
over it if you have time and reread it.
Well, when you reread it with this
inflection, this is actually the answer.
Like two are obviously not it, but
they've made it so ambiguous that if you
over infer hello, um then you're going
to trip yourself up. And she looked at
me and she said, "Don't ever do that.
Don't do what I tell everybody else to
do. Your gut instinct is 90% right. like
go with your gut instinct every time.
>> And I've taken that advice with me
through the rest of my life. I still
would make bad well I used to make bad
decisions still because I wasn't
listening to myself. When I don't listen
to my gut and it's hard if you don't
have that little voice,
>> it's really hard to find it.
>> Yeah.
>> Because you might not you might
genetically not have it, but you might.
It's just like this. Sometimes it can be
this little nagging thing and sometimes
it can be it just doesn't feel right.
I'm not walking into that store or it
just
>> this my gut just says
>> D is the answer.
>> Lo and behold because somewhere in your
brain is picking up on something
contextually or you've noticed
something. I don't know how to explain
it but it was one of the best pieces of
advice I ever got. Just like do you need
it?
>> Yeah.
>> And I edited out the thing that was
making everybody laugh and I because my
thought was well DVDs are big now with
at the university level. I'll just put
the bonus scene on the DVD. It'll just
be bonus. It'll be extra features.
>> Yeah, there you go.
>> You know, and so I was like, there's
always a place for something just like
you're talking about. You've created a
piece of music or whatever that people
may not enjoy, but you have it in your
arsenal,
>> right?
>> So, you can use it at some point. You
can pull it out. There are mixes that I
have sitting there that I never
completed or that I created 15 years
ago. I was like, I've sent them to some
of the producers for shows and been
like, "Hey, what do you think about
using something like this?"
>> Yeah.
>> Oh my gosh, love it. Thank you. Um,
>> it's just sitting there. Yeah.
>> Yeah. It's just sitting there and I'
I've already taken care of it. And
you're getting paid for work that you
were just,
>> you know,
>> Yeah.
>> doing. But there's a time and a place
for everything.
>> Yeah. Yeah. 100%. I mean, well, and and
also everything that you do is making
you a little bit better the next time
you do it. So even if you don't that
never sees the light of the day, just by
creating it, you've now improved your
skills to some degree, right?
>> Well, absolutely. It's it's it's that I
think that's where apprenticeships, our
lack of apprenticeships in society hurt
us
>> and that, you know, everything is go to
college, do it this way, do it that way.
But there's so much trade and skill
you can learn on YouTube, you can learn
knowledge through books. We have so many
avenues where we can find knowledge. I'm
not worried about that. College doesn't
set you up always for anything that's a
trade. You got to be hands-on with it.
>> And that's where having an
apprenticeship is really helpful. And a
work practicum isn't necessarily going
to give that to you. It might give you
the end to get to get there, but I've
just kind of that's why I like the micro
stuff when you do. Are you familiar with
micro and dirty jobs? Yeah. Yeah. And he
has he has a whole new series now. I
don't watch all of them, but he's one of
those shows that I like to watch because
it's kind of like, oh, I get to learn
about something different, you know. Or
Mark Mark, what's his name that used to
do Double Dare, but he did the Food
Networks, the sweets that made sweets,
or you know, this is how these things
are made, and you go to the factory.
It's very Sesame Street. It's very, you
know, how crayons are made kind of
situation. But you're learning the
basics of how, oh, this is the network.
This is the framework. This is the this.
This is the that. So, I don't know.
Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Well, okay.
>> It's a weird place to end. Sorry.
>> Well, no. Well, no, not really. I mean,
I I've a lot of it is very cohesive,
actually. I was trying to think of a way
to um you know, tie tie the bow on
things like I was trying to think of
like, you know what? So, okay. So, what
would you say you've collectively
learned? So, a lot of me I want to I
want to suggest. So, you know, like in
Zen they have beginner's mind, right?
And that's like one of the most
powerful. I mean, dude, if you apply
beginner's mind to like everything in
your life all the time, all day, you're
just going to succeed. You're just going
to continually learn. You're just going
to like be able to approach things in a
new way. Um, I I think beginner's mind
is very important. Um, creating a space
for other people to
uh, you know, not only make a mistake,
but like try things. I feel like that's
what I'm hearing from you. Like, you
know, your teacher created this
environment for you guys to create.
you're learning real world things, but
she didn't give you such a high ceiling
to where you're like floating off earth,
you know, she reeled you back in. Um, so
I don't know. Okay. So, so what do you
think about like your general looking
back at what you just shared, not just
your mentors, but also like what you
have shared as as a mentor like
imagining people are learning from you
as well.
>> What what are some through lines for
you? Like what are some common things
like what is what is kind of your if you
had to say a sentence of like hey man
this is important learn this if you're a
young person listening do you have
anything that comes to mind for you
>> it's going to be a lot of t-shirt wisdom
>> live baby
seriously it's two things can be true at
once
>> that's I mean
be open to the possibility that there's
another way to do things may not work in
the situation But they're, you know, and
that comes from both sides as we talked
before about I need you to do it this
way in this moment. But that person also
needs to realize, oh, you could still
learn something as well. Somebody coming
up that's younger who is more used to
technology might have a shortcut that
you've never learned. So, so it works
both ways. And that's one of the reasons
I love working with students. It really
is because they'll have a trick that I
didn't learn and then I'll I had one
student say was watching me on a
lightboard and I was doing a lot of copy
paste of cues and I said yeah it's a lot
of data entry but it's not all
creativity it's data entry I got to I
have to sit here and go 365 through 372
copy to Q 42
enter then go back and change the colors
on them. It's it's a lot of procedural
work, but if you can think ahead, you
can use the lights to your advantage.
You can use what they naturally do.
Because he went, "Wait, you're just
using that the lights track a certain
way and you're not creating you're not
blinding your cues. You're not doing
like, no, I just know I need my lights.
I want them here to do this and I want
them to sweep there. So, I'll start
here. Set that Q. Go back a Q. Record
the next thing the the where I want it
to start." And then now it's going to
sweep and do what I want it to do. And
then I'll put a time. I'll change the
time on it to six seconds because it's a
ballad and I just want it to sweep. And
then I don't have to do four cues. I
don't have to sit there and cue it in
blind and do the this and do the that.
Like I don't have to do all that extra
work because work smarter not harder.
Sometimes this is a thing that I need to
work with. You do have to work harder.
Like sometimes you have to put effort
into things.
>> So much has come naturally to me
especially in the artistic sense.
Sometimes you do have to put effort into
it. So that would be something I'd say
as well.
>> Yeah,
>> sometimes you have to put effort in.
Communication requires listening.
>> If you're not listening, you're not
communicating. Period. You're just
you're pontificating. It's like when
people get heated and they start talking
about politics or religion or something
like that. They're social constructs.
They It all is no matter how we as
society have made them up. So you can
cherrypick from them. It's not a lock
stalk one way to do things. And if you
try to find commonality with somebody
and you stop yelling at each other,
>> yeah,
>> people will tune you out or yell back at
you if you yell. So if we can lower the
temperature, which sounds so p
condescending or pandering, but it's
like no, if we can all just take a be
and go maybe we are trying to say the
same thing or we want the same outcome.
We don't agree by the method by which we
get there, but at least we both want the
same thing. Yay, commonality. I'd rather
find commonality with people than be
divisive. I don't need to sow discord.
It's It doesn't serve me anything in my
life, but don't think I don't get
passionate.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. I mean, finding the commonality is
a way in. I always say like like if you
can find a way that you agree, it opens
the door and now you can really have a
conversation because if you're just
starting where you disagree, you're not
going to get very far.
>> Exactly. But then there's the
communication part where you have to
listen to each other and then you have
to articulate because you might find out
you really are saying the same thing.
It's just one key component that's not.
Um I've kind of lost track of where I
was going to go with my t-shirt wisdom
for what you said were saying,
>> but
>> well, we have a lot of t-shirt wisdom
out here. I feel like a lot of our uh a
lot of our quotes are like perfect.
There's been a lot of things where the
your response has been like, "Oh, that's
so perfect." So, people can uh print
their own shirts. I'll I'll have AI find
a quote in here and make it make a
t-shirt company.
>> What you don't know, you don't know what
you don't know. If you were not taught
it, if you were not exposed to it, you
you cannot expect people to be at your
level. That was a problem that I had. I
was so ahead with certain things in
life, I had to unlearn my own
programming. I had to sit there and go,
people aren't as operating on your
level. You know what I mean? And I don't
mean like a level above like like we're
just on two completely different islands
and your interests are not my interest.
So I have to find a way in or a way to
explain myself,
>> you know, and so that's going to be
incumbent upon me to take more time and
more energy if I want to elicit a
different response. Yeah.
>> And it and I feel like it works well.
I've seen I asked someone a colleague of
mine one time and it was in an
educational type environment why they
interacted with a student a specific way
and the response was I wanted them to
think for themselves and I wanted them
to
what was the word that he used? I'm
going to say it my way but make
connections and um what's the word I'm
trying to find? It's a very specific
word. It's when you think for yourself,
you're making connections. You You're
not thinking abstractly, but you are
just innately or intuitively trying to
find the next step or whatever. And the
word escapes me and I'll remember it at
2 a.m., but I I just walked away from
that and went, "Oh, what you don't
realize is they've never been taught
that."
So it is incumbent upon you in this
moment that if that's what you're trying
to teach them, you then have to create
the safe the safe space but the but the
space where you can fail and you can say
that's not that's not how you do it. Let
me show you the groundwork or the basic
framework of how to think to the next
level, how to get to the next part.
You're not being taught that in school.
You're taught to lather, rinse, repeat.
But if you can work with somebody and
realize, oh, you just don't understand
because you've never been exposed. Okay,
cool. Let me explain this to you really
quickly. I don't have the time to, but
I'm going to really quickly like go with
me on this rapid fire. Happens quite a
lot for me. And it's like, okay, we're
we're we're going to do it this way.
Then they can take that, they can sleep
on it. They can do whatever they need to
do. And at some point, they're going to
end up in another situation cuz it's
happened to me where you're like,
>> and it connects. And when it f and when
it connects, it's the best feeling. And
then they know your expectation as well.
>> Right. Right.
>> Because if you don't, how how can you
get upset with somebody
>> if you don't explain your expectation,
>> right? Yeah. Hey, you should have read
my mind better.
>> Very much so. Like it's like I'm I'm
telegraphing it. Well, you didn't state
it. Well, I stated this. I'm like, ah, I
get it. I see how
the inference that would be made. I see
your inference, but I see what I
extrapolated from it. And once again,
now me as the person who said that needs
to go, oh, I probably should have worded
that better,
>> right?
>> Or I once again, that's the
communication part of it. But that's
kind of
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I mean, because if you
>> I I I like it because I feel like it's
you taking extreme responsibility for
it. like you're not trying to, you know,
make them feel bad for what they do and
don't know or like um yeah, you're
you're like, "Okay, there's clearly a
way that I could communicate this
differently to where it makes sense for
them or at least it helps them more
because clearly we're not on the same
page right now." But so I mean that that
alone is a good, you know, leadership
move, I would say, because you know,
you're taking responsibility for what
can I do in this situation.
>> Well, thank you. It's it's it's kind of
like I think we all sit here and
analysis par I can get analysis over
analysis paralysis very easily and I
think people in g because you just
overthink it. So you never finish a
project or you never you never launch
it. There's so much stuff that I have
that I've never put into the digital
sphere
>> because you just kind of go, "Oh, it's
not where I want it to be." And at some
point you just have to let it free and
do what it's going to do. But working in
Oh gosh, I was going somewhere with
that. Dang it. I was going somewhere
very specific with it. Uh over analysis
paralysis,
letting it free. Oh, random example.
>> Yeah.
>> Britney Spears. A long time ago, she
made headlines when her children were
babies for driving on the California
freeway with her baby in her lap. Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Here's the thing. When you grow up in
the 80s and 90s in rural Louisiana,
Mississippi, Texas, Arkansas, wherever
and you're on your own property or on
back roads,
we weren't dealing with airbags. We
weren't dealing with any of this stuff.
You'd sit on a tractor in somebody's lap
and you'd pretend steer somebody else
always. It's normal. So, if you've never
been exposed or told that that you can't
do that because you have an airbag in
the car because this is this and you're
in fight or flight mode because the
paparazzi is chasing you and you just
grab your child and go,
>> but you present her as this crazy
nutter, right?
>> That that it's No, it's it's something
the moment that I saw it, I just felt so
badly for her because she's like six
months older than I am. So, I sit there
and I'm like, I know better. But I know
better because I understand these
things. I grew up riding in the front
seat of the car as a toddler of a
Cadillac. There weren't airbags and
there you put the armrest down. I wasn't
even in a car seat. You'd latch it in
and the arm would come flying up and you
go flying back into the hole that was
there, right? Trying to claw your way
out of it. You were perfectly fine. You
know, how many generations of people
produced this younger generation of
people that are so worried about all of
these things? Airbags are an issue, you
know, in an automobile. I'm not saying
put your child in the car and don't
don't follow rules. What I'm saying is
you only know what you know.
>> And if you don't even know the question
to ask to get new information, how are
you supposed to do that?
>> And so then you're just stifled.
>> Yeah. And it almost becomes
self-censoring and self-sabotage at some
point. And I don't like that. And when I
work a crew or a team, I like people
that are independent. And I can trust
that you're going to do the job that you
need to do.
>> I don't need to I'm type A, but I don't
need to sit on you with with a thumb.
You know what I mean? I don't need to
You can be commanding without being
demanding.
>> You can you don't have to yell at
people. You don't have to do this thing,
but you need to I can use tone of voice,
but if I need to get loud, I can get
loud. I need to be able to have that
room to push there. I need to be able to
become stern. If you start stern, you
can't become stern.
And on a crew, I trust you to do your
job. You were hired to do something. If
I need you to do it differently, I need
to then come in and communicate. I need
you to do it this way.
>> Right?
>> That's how you would do it with a
performer. You're singing it this way. I
love that you came in and gave me I put
a spell on you and it was a combo of the
original version and the Hocus Pocus B
Midler version and you gave me this this
really cool hybrid version. But what
we're doing they're going to expect the
B Midler version. I'm going to need you
to pull that midler for me. But if you
want to go up the octave and outshine
her because you can, you know, because
you because you can give me that
highend.
>> Yeah,
>> go for it. You know what I mean? Like
you can take that autonomy on your
performance, but I need this little
correction from you.
>> Right. Right. Right.
>> But and but that's not even the
compliment sandwich because I genuinely
loved what you did. I just they're going
to expect this.
>> Yeah.
>> Just like Curtis, I need you to edit the
song out of the mix. I don't need people
turning around to me saying that's the
one song that they remembered because it
was too hard or it was too this or it
was too that, you know? So, it's I guess
it comes full circle at some point.
>> Yeah. Yeah, it does. I mean, well, in
your ability to,
you know, communicate with that person
and not, you know, like we said, expect
them to kind of read your mind or come
from the exact same place that you came
from. Like, you know, expect that they
had the exact same upbringing as you and
they've had all the same meetings as you
and blah blah blah. Like, hey, can't you
read the room? You need to sing it this
way. Like, why are you even wasting my
time with the rehearsal? You're not
approaching it like that. You know,
you're hearing where they're coming
from. Cool. You clearly have these
skills, but we're going to take it this
way. You know, that's where Yeah.
balance of being polite, kind,
understanding, but also stern like,
"Hey, I get that's cool that you did it
that way. I like that a lot. I would
love to hear it again, but for this
show, we got to do it this way." So,
yeah, I think um man, I a lot of our
communication is,
man, it really is multiaceted, right?
Like there's so many different things
that do need to happen at once. It's
like communication is a constant. Like,
it's not just all right, cool, I'm a
good communicator now. It's like every
day there's a new opportunity to learn
how to communicate to understand when we
say things a certain way or a certain,
you know, uh, energy that we bring or a
mood that we bring to certain people.
Okay, I just shut them down on accident
because I was too certain with them, you
know. So, it's it's a constant eb and
flow, you know, communication seems like
it's a it's quite the dance, I feel
like, is a good
>> very much so. And it's a it's definitely
a partner dance. And what's interesting
also about that
is don't beat yourself up too badly when
you do screw it up.
>> Like I can sit there on that one little
thing from 30 years ago going, "Dang it,
had I just it would have elicited a
different response and I could have
fixed it." Well, hindsight's 2020
usually. And you then extrapolate from
that. Don't repeat the mistake. Don't do
it again. if you see yourself repeating
a pattern that's going to elicit that
response.
>> Yeah,
>> it's it's incumbent upon you as that
person to correct it. So, there's
nothing wrong with looking back
>> and kind of beating yourself up a little
bit over it. Then do something with it.
Be productive with it. And
>> don't beat yourself up for things that
you do in a crisis situation. You do the
best that you can with the information
you have in that time and in that
moment.
That's that's kind of the mantra we've
always had around our household. Like
crisis situation decisions, you cannot
go back and look at those and say, "Oh,
well, I should have done this better."
>> And half of that's going to be
communication. Like, oh, if I only I had
moved this here versus there,
>> man.
>> You can't
>> Yeah.
>> I would I was just saying that's
actually like uh it's it's so sweet how
that actually landed really with me
personally. I didn't expect that. like
don't don't uh don't beat yourself up
about how you reacted in a crisis
situation. I don't for whatever reason I
was like oh I needed to hear that. I
don't know what what it's even
personally applying to but I like that a
lot. I think that is a very useful thing
to hear. I mean, I think when you the
outworld world sees you a certain way
and don't realize that you've been
dealing with a whole bunch of stuff and
you're just you're not just juggling
plates, but the world around you is
you're on shifting ground and all the
different things.
You cannot beat yourself up because in
this situation, you had to make a
decision. You were put on a timeline and
your back was against a wall or on just
a show. we can make it just as simple as
a show. Like I called I said go with the
music and no don't go with the music. I
was like well I screwed that one up you
know. Oh no the whole show's burned
down. No it's not you know but
>> it is a place where you can beat
yourself up. And so if you can that's
another thing on set it doesn't do me
any good. Some people go straight to the
yelling and if you've coiled cable
improperly, they will knot it up for you
and make you redo it. And that's how I
that's how I was taught. You know that
by that road, I didn't like it. So, I
don't do it that way. You know, you if
you've screwed up, you know, you screwed
up.
>> So, all I have to say is,
>> yeah, I know, but we got to finish the
show. We'll discuss this later. We'll
figure it out later. But
>> right now, I mean, I'm not happy, but
just don't do it again. we have to move
forward.
>> Yeah.
>> There's no need for me to throw a temper
tantrum.
>> Only in a safety situation
>> do I need to like you start getting into
that head space. It's like no, we got to
protect something, a person or you know,
whatever. But outside of that,
>> don't beat yourself up.
>> Try not to try try not to. It's easier
said than done.
>> Yeah. I mean, as as a as a person who
beats myself up often, that is always
something that I'm uh it does help me
have compassion for other people,
though. Because a lot of times if I'm in
a situation where it's like, you know,
I'm a director and somebody messes
something up. I don't need to give them
the lecture cuz I know pretty dang well
most of the people I work with, they're
already beating themselves up about it.
They're already wishing they wouldn't
have done it. They're very aware of the
mistake they made. And it's like, is it
genuinely that helpful to like my future
of working with this person or the show
at hand that's still going on for me to
berate them in this moment? And the
answer is going to be no. Uh, a lot of
times the I like to use the saying weak
arms. Um, if if in that moment I'm
stressed out and I can't handle the
stress of like what just happened or I'm
like, "Oh no, I'm going to lose my job
because this camera person just messed
up or whatever," it's on me to like have
a little bit of strength in my arms and
hold a little bit of my emotions, a
little bit of my frustration. If my arms
are so weak that the second I get
frustrated and angry, I need to hand it
to someone, then I need to go I need to
work out, you know, like I need to get
in the gym. So, it's like uh me,
I never want to catch myself with weak
arms in those situations where I just
wasn't able to handle my own stress and
so I took it out on somebody else. So,
it just it's just a useful
>> Well, it's human and we've all done it
in different and variety of ways and you
know, just trying to make
>> Yeah. It Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Well, no. I just I just went into an
entirely different thought process that
would have gone on another tangent.
>> Well, that's the thing about podcast is
we could just keep on going forever. But
uh I I will I will save whoever's still
listening at this point. I'll save you
another hour and a half of your time at
least until unless Curtis and I do
another one in the future. Um but uh
man, I I do kind of want to round the
corner here uh with with our pod. Um so
I
>> chop it up and just edit fix it in post.
>> Yeah. Yeah, I know. sometime not. Dude,
I I I'm a person who listens to very
long podcasts. I listen to them all the
way. I love long podcasts. So, you know,
as much as there's probably people that
are like, "Dude, you can't just ramble
on forever." I don't know. I like
listening to a ramble on forever myself.
So, there's people out there who do. Um
and I and I will clip it up. But I do
want to just to tie the bow on the end
here. Um last couple minutes,
>> I want to ask you an impossible
question. Um
>> Okay.
>> And it could have something to do with
what we've talked about and it could
have nothing to do. So, I'll give you a
moment to to think about it, but I
always like this very difficult question
of Curtis. What does the world need more
of right now?
>> I automatically go to love, sweet love.
>> I know. I I I set it up. The name is
Junkyard Love, so I set it up. But yeah,
um there's no wrong or right answer, but
anything that comes to mind, what what
does the world need more of? What do
people need more? What do people need to
hear? Anything
>> backarak? No. Um,
who?
>> A one-word answer that I I don't know
why this word popped into my head.
Insight.
>> Tell me more.
>> I don't know why insight I don't know
why that was the word that popped into
my head, but it's
you can Insight can be introspective.
Insight can be learning about something,
but it's that little bit of extra
information. There's always something
you don't know.
>> Yeah.
>> And you can perceive yourself as
learned. You can have the credentials
that say that. There's always something
we can work on. There's always something
that we can do. Now, that can bleed over
into somebody thinking, "Well, whatever
I do for you is never enough." That's
not what I mean. It kind of goes back to
play to your strengths, work on your
weaknesses, hide your faults. It's it's
it's that there's always something to
learn and there's another way to do
things.
>> So
maybe there's compassion in with that,
but it's understanding,
>> insight, and understanding. Now, now I
have Shar's love and understanding stuck
in my head.
But, but in all seriousness, it's I
think it's
there's there's there's always another
keystone,
>> another lynch pin, another another
nugget,
>> like an opening. Yeah.
>> Yes. Exactly. And or or another way that
you can build on to what you know.
There's another tool for your belt or
your toolbox. there's something else you
can put in your arsenal so that you can
take it out and use it as a tool as
opposed to saying this is the entirety
of what something is.
>> So I think it's it's more about having
more tools in your tool belt and that
requires knowing that there's just
something else. There's one more thing.
>> Dude, I'm actually I I really like the
word insight. I think that's actually a
really good one. It's a it's a it's a
word that I I'm I'm a certified
meditation teacher on the app Insight
Timer by the way for anybody listening.
So that that comes to mind. But insight
I love that a lot. That is like an
opening like a sudden it makes me think
of magic almost like there's always a
new opportunity if you just have the
insight. And I think it's one of those
words that any listener and even me I
think I'm going to just like pop that
word into my mind periodically for the
next couple weeks and just see what
comes up. Like insight like not even
like what's the insight I could have
about this? It's not even that deep.
Just insight and then like lay that word
over into into any situation and kind of
see what opens up. Right.
>> Well, think about it. It's two words
combined in
>> sight.
>> It's a compound word.
>> So, there's a definition, but each word
has its own meaning. And then there's
the combined definition of the two words
together.
>> I'm so glad you found that you used that
word. That's so perfect actually
>> because sight is vision.
>> Yeah.
>> How how am I seeing this? How are they
seeing this
>> in sight? So introspective or you're
seeing into something or someone or a
situation or whatever. And it's, you
know,
>> brilliant. I love it.
>> Thank you.
>> Cool. Yeah. No, that that's so great. Um
Okay, man. Well, hey, man. Thank you so
much for your time. I appreciate all
this. This was so great. I love that. Uh
thank you for for running with the the
free flow style that I do here, man. I I
think that uh you brought up some like
super incredible things that I don't
think my notes would have ever touched
otherwise. So, I'm I'm really glad that
you were willing to kind of play with me
here, man. I had a lot of fun.
>> Yeah. No worries. I I I think it I think
this kind of vibe works really well.
It's it's loose loose structure.
>> Yeah. Yeah. That's like I said, that's
what I like listening to and that's
where when I first got into podcast,
man, people would stumble just kind of
the rambling conversational back and
forth. They would say something like two
and a half hours in on a podcast that
I'd go, "Hold up, dude. paused that that
just changed my life. like what did they
just like a random one little sentence
of them laughing about a you know a fart
joke or something two hours in and
somehow that is that is exactly you know
we're all looking for that real
authentic um you know podcasts aren't
planned they're just conversations so I
think there's really some great stuff in
there
>> not to belver this but I do have a
question for you now
>> please ask
>> it's going to be I'll get to the reason
why I'm asking it what are you listening
to right now like as in in your personal
life. What either artist or album or
song or compilation of things like five
tracks or something? What What has been
your go-to recently as of this date?
I've
>> been listening to
I'm drawn to
I'm pretty into like my my spiritual
lectures and those sorts of things. Um,
I really like like like Ram Doss, Tara
Brock, those sorts of things. Um, I
think what I'm I'm going to go for my
answer would be there's these mixes that
this creator Dirty Zen makes. He's
actually been on this podcast.
>> Um, and they're chillstep, the music
genre of chillstep, so it's like melodic
dubstep, but then they have spiritual
lectures laid over the top of them.
>> And I love them so much, but I also that
is something that I continuously go back
to. like I go on a walk and if I can't
really find something or I'm not in the
middle of a book that's really tugging
at me to listen to on Audible, um I will
I'll put on one of those mixes. So,
Chillstep uh spiritual mixes, check them
out online. Dirty Zen, one word.
>> Awesome. Cool.
>> That's my response.
>> Do do you have one that you've been
listening to? Do you have
>> Oh, oddly enough, it's it's
two different things very specifically.
I mean, other than like your general
podcast stuff and just the kind of stuff
that you would put on and listen to, but
music genre wise, I've watched Billy
Corgan has a new podcast called The
Magnificent Ones. Billy Corgan, for
those that don't know, is the lead
singer of the Smashing Pumpkins. He
formed the band. He's the composer
really of all their work. You would know
1979, Tonight, those songs if you're not
familiar with the band. But he was
interviewing Carney Wilson of Wilson
Phillips. She is the daughter of Brian
Wilson, the Beach Boys.
>> And in 1990, I received the cassette,
the first Wilson Phillips album, and it
was mine. It wasn't like my parents. It
was my cassette. And watching this
interview, this podcast made me want to
go back and listen to their music
because it's a trio,
the children of the Mamas and the Papas
and the Beach Boys. So, it's the two of
the Brian the Beach Boy daughters and
then China Phillips and Wilson Phillips.
They have these amazing harmonies and um
oh my gosh, who who
I just lost his name. The the producer
on the album did Jagged Little Pill and
Katie Perry's first album. I don't know
if he did the some of Glenn Ballard.
Glenn B. So, he did Alennena's Jagged
Little Pill and then he he ended up
doing some of the early Katy Perry
stuff, like really early. Uh, and just
going back and listening through that
album and listening through now knowing
some of the stories behind their in
their early 20s and horrible
relationships and
how like a 8-year-old, nineyear-old is
vibing with,
>> you know, what a 20 year old female is
dealing with, but and you know, Hold On,
the big song that everybody knows, it's
I think at the end of Bridesmaids or one
of those movies. Uh but their biggest
single hold on is literally about I need
to hold on for one more day and things
will just go your way but hold on like
my grandfather always said go take a nap
>> sleep something will always look
brighter in the morning
>> you you you don't and I say it's too
late for solutions to be solved in the
setting sun like right now we can't fix
this
>> that one too like that
>> well I kind of pulled that from a
garbage lyric the band garbage
has has a lyric in one of her songs that
says, "It's too late for solutions to be
solved in the setting sun." And so I've
taken that little nugget, a lot of my
stuff will go back to music, but it's
too late for solutions to be solved in
the setting sun. We'll figure it out
tomorrow. Like we can sit here and beat
ourselves up tonight about it
>> or we can accept
>> it is what it is and we'll fix it, but
we just have to get up early
>> kind of thing. Yeah.
>> And the other thing I've been listening
to is Oasis.
>> This morning was an Oasis. This morning,
so it's Wilson Phillips and Oasis
because you get much opposite. Brit pop
and pop pop. Like vocal harmony pop.
>> We all got more than one mood. That's
for sure. You know, I uh I I throw in my
second that I've been listening to a lot
is John Bellian. Do you know him? He's a
producer, singer, songwriter. Um he's
he's written for like Rihanna and Bieber
and he's a good um behind the scenes for
sure, but he's he's my favorite artist.
I've seen him like nine times.
I'm really not a stan or a super fan of
anybody but him. He's the only person
that I'm John Bellian. You have to check
him out. He's a great producer. Yeah.
>> Is it Is it like pop R&B kind of hybrid?
Okay.
>> Pop I would say very much. He does rap
but he's um he's a producer and a beat
maker. So his beats are are really um
>> they're very original. Like you you'll
recognize like oh he has a very original
sound for sure. He has like a Jay Dilla
kind of boom bat uh east coast New York
vibe, but he's also very like poppy,
very like like beautiful lyrics, very
sentimental, like hard-hitting, deep
stuff. Okay.
>> Um you'll have you'll have to explore
him and let me know. But that's that's
the other person I'm listening to. John
Bellian ton.
>> John Bellian. John Bellian. John
Bellian. Okay. Well, what's funny is
that's Butch Walker for me.
>> Butch Walker. Okay.
>> Butch Walker I love especially his Let's
Go Out Tonight's album.
>> He used to be part of a band called
Marvelous 3 that I love. Um, so that
first Marvelous 3 album and then
I love his solo work, but he writes a
lot with Pink and a lot of the punk pop
people. Uh, yeah.
>> I don't know.
>> Yeah. Let's Go Out Tonight. Butch Walker
is That's the
>> It's the Butch Walker and the Let's Go
Out Tonight, but you'll find it easily
on Spotify. Like you'll know it as soon
as you see. It's very kind of glam rock
inspired. It's like kind of rockabilly,
glam rock, pop rock. Like it's it's a
really
>> cool. Okay, I made you up, man. Yeah,
you know how I am with me. I love more
than I I like more than I dislike.
That's what I always say with music. I
there's too much good me I don't I don't
know how people don't like so much
different genres. There's just so much
good music.
>> I sit there and say even if I don't like
an artist or an album, I can find one
song. It may be the remix. It may be the
acoustic version. It may be something
else, but I can find something. I can
sit there and go gh. But I can find that
one thing, but I may have to troll a
little bit to find some B-side or some
deep cut.
>> Yeah.
>> But I'll take the time to do it if I
need to.
>> Well, and I like to treat the same thing
with books. I like to treat life like if
somebody suggests an album or like they
say, "Hey, this is my favorite album or
I've been listening to this a lot
lately." I like to treat the same thing
as I do with books. If somebody mentions
that, I feel like it means I should at
least check it out. Like I I like You
get so many dope albums if you just
listen up to people suggesting what they
like. It's great.
>> Exactly. Well, I don't want to keep you
any longer. I know.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Let me end this thing. Um,
>> what's funny is I thought I wasn't even
going to have 90 minutes for you. I was
like, I mean, I can talk a lot, but Oh,
no. This will be this will be short and
easy that you're going to have to edit.
Sorry.
>> No, no, we're good, man. I I love it.
This is exactly how I want it to go.
It's that really is how it how it ends
up happening is is you just get talking
with somebody and and um you know, even
through Zoom, honestly, like through
Zoom, it's not in person, so it is a
little different, but even through Zoom,
you can catch a vibe pretty quick. And
that's all people. That's how I am on
the phone. But I was on the phone as a
toddler. Like there were pictures of me
on the phone with my grandma. Like it
literally I when I say I'm lequacious,
like literally I will be on the phone
with a friend for two hours. I don't
have to see you. I don't have to
FaceTime you. I don't have to I don't
have to see you. I can do go about my
day, multitask, and we can have a
conversation and we can hang it up and
in a few hours to a month can go by and
we can pick it right back up where we
need to
>> and I think that's that's a skill. Not
everybody has that. So,
>> yeah. Yeah.
>> Well, it's a good skill. Hopefully
people listening uh have picked up on
some of your skills now and hopefully
they're they're better for it. So, um
hey listeners, I love you. Thank you for
hanging with us. We'll see you next
episode. Please check out the
description, the bio down below. If you
want to explore any more of Curtis's
work, please do so. All the links are
below. And uh you know what I always say
at the end of these episodes is if you
haven't drank any water today, you're
out of your damn mind. What are you
doing? Drink some water. If you haven't
stretched today, you're also out of your
damn mind. Stretch water. That's what
I'm talking about. I got my jug right
here, dude.
>> Yep. I uh Yeah. So, uh, stretch, drink
water, love yourself, and if you enjoyed
this episode, subscribe, follow,
comment, all of that. I appreciate it.
We will see you next episode. I'm going
to end this recording. Bye, everybody.
Oh, wait. Hold on. Let me
[Music]
n
Knowledge is power.
Reality is
[Music]
>> Junkyard Love A guest.